dark factory today. And I know it sounds
kind of spooky, but I'll start things
off by explaining what that actually is.
This is going to be a little bit more of
a casual live stream. So, I did a live
stream over the weekend where I dove
really deep into Archon, the new
open-source harness builder.
And so, I'm going to be actually be
using this a lot today, but I want to
just do more like a live building
session. So, I'll still like be sure to
explain everything that I'm doing and
have a good time for Q&A and stuff, but
it's going to be a little bit more like
you guys just get to see the inside of a
process that I'm starting here with a
public experiment that I'm calling the
dark factory.
And so, I've got my left monitor open up
here with all of your guys' comments in
the chat, and then my right monitor
where I have my recording software, and
then I've got my screen in the middle
here. So, when you see me looking
around, that's what I'm doing.
But yeah, this is just going to be like
a a good like two two and a half hours
I'm thinking of streaming for where I'm
going to be building the dark factory in
public with you guys, and even opening
this up fully to the public in a couple
weeks here. I'll talk about that means
as well, but I I need to explain first
what the heck a dark factory actually
is. So, I'll I'll cover the basics for
you guys. I think you'll find it really
really interesting.
Because this is like the peak evolution
of AI coding. Not that a dark factory is
going to give you the most reliable
results, but it is the way to get the
most control possible to your AI coding
assistants when they're working on a
code base. So, the idea of the dark
factory, it originated actually in the
late I think like 1980s, 1990s. There
were some companies in China that were
running physical production lines with
only robots. And so, the physical
location only had robots in it, so they
didn't even have to have the lights on,
right? There's no need to pay for
electricity when there's no humans
operating in the facility.
And so, Dan Shapiro, I believe he's the
first one that took [clears throat] this
idea of the dark factory and applied it
to code bases. So, using generative AI
to completely manage a code base all the
way from ideation, implementation, code
review, merging pull requests, handling
releases, like actually shipping the
code as well. That is what a dark
factory is. And I think the best way to
explain it is to go through his article
here.
So, he put this out just at the end of
January this year. And he talks about
the five levels of AI coding. A lot of
us are at level like three or four right
now. So, I I think like seeing where
you're at and then like how far we can
take things with the dark factory with
his analogy will
like really help you understand like
exactly what the heck a dark factory is.
And so, yeah, let me go and share my
screen here with this blog article. I
actually meant to be sharing my screen
earlier, so that's my bad, but yeah, so
let's take a look at this together here.
So, this is Dan Shapiro's post
So, the five levels from spicy auto
complete to the dark factory.
And so, level zero, this is how I
started using AI to help me code.
Probably the same for a lot of you guys
that came from an engineering
background. You were writing code
yourself before, and then you slowly
start leaning on AI more and more. So, I
don't know why he calls it spicy auto
complete, but hey, I love it, so I'm I'm
for it. So, and in this [snorts] case,
the analogy that he uses throughout the
different levels is our control of a
vehicle.
So, at level zero, we're still driving.
You can even think of it as like stick
shift, right? Like super manual. We are
managing the vehicle. And so, the AI
coding assistant or even just like the
large language model serves as a
reference tool or an enhanced search.
So, it's like a smarter stack overflow
if you guys have used stack overflow in
the past. And so, here the developer
manually writes all the code. We're just
using AI as an advisor. So, like help me
with this code snippet or give me an
idea for how I can implement this, but
we still are the ones hands on the
keyboard writing the actual code.
So, hopefully most of us aren't at this
step anymore. Um I know some people
still are cuz that's what what they're
comfortable with, and that's totally
okay. Uh but then we go into level one.
This is the coding intern. So, you can
think of it like cruise control. You
still have your hands on the wheel, but
at least AI is managing something or
like the car is managing keeping you at
a certain speed like 65 mph. So, here
the AI writes the unimportant or
boilerplate code. So, you're still doing
most of the work yourself, but for the
things that you don't require much trust
in the large language model, you're
starting to hand it over.
That's the coding intern.
And by the way, when we get to level
five, I'll talk about how I'm actually
building it myself. So, we'll we'll get
there, but I want to kind of give the
basis for you here. So, we then get to
level two, the junior developer. This is
the pair programmer. So, we start to
relax a little bit. We only have one
hand on the wheel instead of two. So,
the developer and AI trade off control.
So, there are legitimately some more
complex tasks that we are delegating to
the coding agent, but not all of the
time. We still are the ones writing the
code a lot.
And then we get to level three. And so,
this is, you know, like the self-driving
cars now, right? Like you got hands off
the wheel, but you're still paying
attention to the road. And so, the AI is
generating a majority of the code base,
but you're still reviewing everything
that the AI does. Like you're watching
the road constantly, and you're going to
be nitpicky. You're going to review
plans, you're going to give feedback,
you're going to review the code like the
pull requests before you merge it.
You're always the bottleneck for
verification before progressing. That's
level three. And honestly, that's where
most of us are. And you know, like when
I teach AI coding on my channel and in
the Dynamis community,
level three is actually what I generally
recommend. Because this is the furthest
you can push it right now and still get
the most reliable results possible. So,
at level four,
um this is where we get into the
engineering team. When we get into
harnesses for longer running tasks. And
so, this is where you actually get to
fall asleep at the wheel. So, you let
the AI run unattended for long periods
handling very complex tasks. And so, you
think of harnesses like the Rel loop or
Anthropic's harness giving your second
brain the ability to handle issues and
pull requests end to end. So, here you
still are going to check the final
results. Like at some point, you're
going to you're going to wake up and
just like make sure the car is actually
driving you to the right place, and you
know, take your put your hands on the
wheel if you need to, but for the most
part, you're trusting the coding agent
to handle insanely long sets of work.
So, level four, I I wouldn't say this is
like the most reliable at this point. If
you want to ship the most reliable
production code possible, you're still
at level three. Cuz you're still going
to monitor everything and be the
bottleneck for verification, but you're
starting to really take yourself out of
the loop with level four,
but there's still the steering wheel,
right? Like there's still the
opportunity for you to step in and fix
things yourself or steer the agents in a
different direction in the middle of
some implementation.
And then that brings us into level five.
And I love the car analogy here cuz you
like you look at level four, and there's
still the steering wheel, like right?
There's still the opportunity for you to
have control, but in level five, your
vehicle looks like this, which someday
we'll get there. That'll that'll be
really cool. The day that I have a
vehicle looks like this. But there's no
there's no steering wheel in this
vehicle. There's not even the option for
us to take the reins if we want. That's
what a dark factory is.
So, the engineer manages the goal in the
system, right? There's still some kind
of console here to provide higher level
direction. We're still going to write
the PRDs. We might manage the some of
the releases, but we're not managing the
code. So, we provide plain English
descriptions, but the agent defines
implementation, writes code, tests,
fixes bugs, and ships. That is a dark
factory.
And that my friend is what we are going
to be building today. I have a good
amount of the system already set up
because I don't want to go through all
the like really boring parts with you,
but I I want to work on the workflows
today. Like actually build the workflows
that are going to manage the entire dark
factory.
Because it's not enough to just point
Claude code at a GitHub repo and say
manage everything. Right? We have to
teach it like how do we want it to
handle issues? What kinds of features
are we going to build into this
application? How do we want to evolve
it? What are the constraints that we
have? How are we going to review code,
right? Like we have to create workflows
to define exactly how we want to write.
So, right? So, like the engineer manages
the goal in the system. I'm talking
about building the system here for this
vehicle.
And so,
um what I'm going to be doing, and this
is this is the most exciting part for
me,
is I'm going to be leveraging Archon
workflows to manage every single part of
the dark factory. So, Archon is my first
ever or it is the first ever open-source
harness for AI coding. First ever
harness builder, sorry. So, you think
about like whatever your process is
right now for software development,
however you work with AI coding
assistants, Archon allows you to build
workflows to package everything up so
that you can build any on any code base.
You can invoke any workflow.
>> [clears throat]
>> Excuse me. You can invoke any workflow
in parallel, and you get reliable
results every single time because you're
taking your process and you're packaging
it up. That's what Archon gives us. And
so, if you're interested more how Archon
works and you haven't seen my content on
it recently, there's a lot that I put
out on my channel recently. So, there's
a couple of live streams that I did,
actually one just two days ago. Um so, I
did it just on Saturday last week.
And then I also have a YouTube video. My
most recent YouTube video where I
covered Archon. So, I'm not going to get
like super deep into an introduction to
Archon today because I already have this
content, but I'm going to be using it as
a very critical part of the workflow, of
the whole system for the Dark Factory
because it's going to drive everything.
I'm going to build Archon workflows to
manage my issues, build Archon workflows
to write the code, review the code,
manage the releases. I'll talk about
what that looks like when I get into my
plan here. So, I have this entire
markdown document
that outlines my entire plan for the
Dark Factory. And I took a lot of
inspiration from
you know other examples of Dark
Factories that are already out there on
the internet. And so, maybe you guys
have heard of the Strong DM use case.
So, Strong DM is a company that they
actually manage a production codebase
with a Dark Factory. They are shipping
pull requests all of the time that don't
have any human review at all. And their
Dark Factory is unfortunately not open
source like mine is going to be for you
guys to see and watch it evolve in real
time.
But they did share something like a PRD.
So, they have this open source spec for
building their Dark Factory. They call
it the Attractor.
And so, we don't have the codebase, but
we do have the plan document that I
guess theoretically you can use to have
your coding agent build out exactly what
they have for managing their codebase
with no humans involved. And so, I did
actually take a lot of inspiration from
the ideas here. If you guys are
interested in any of this, I'm planning
on putting out a YouTube video tomorrow
where I'll have like a more concise
overview of everything and I'll have
links to this all.
I can of course put links to this in the
chat too if you guys are curious. So,
um I will
put a link to this blog post right here.
And then
um I'll put a link to this resource
covering the
Dark the Strong DM Dark Factory. If you
guys want to read through it.
Just want to make sure I give those
to you guys cuz that's a lot of like my
initial research for building a Dark
Factory.
And I'm super fascinated by this. So,
okay, let me be really clear here. I
want to uh we clear on something and
then I'll explain more of that the
architecture that I have for my Archon
Dark Factory.
I know I already said this, but it's
worth repeating. The you're not going to
get the most reliable results with your
coding agent when you give it this much
autonomy. I highly recommend when you're
doing things for real, you put yourself
in the loop, at least reviewing plans
and reviewing code. Those two stages of
the development cycle, I would at least
have those.
So, this is definitely a public
experiment. I'm calling it an experiment
because it might fall completely flat on
its face. We'll see. I mean, I'm going
to put a lot of work into trying to make
it really reliable, but
I have no idea how the codebase is going
to end up evolving when I leave it to
literally manage itself. And so, the
input for the Dark Factory is going to
be a GitHub issue.
So, I as a user and then I'm going to
make this public so you guys can
literally submit GitHub issues as well.
It's going to be so fun when I get this
really running.
And the input is a GitHub issue. And so,
this is either a bug that we've noticed
in the platform as we've tested it as a
user or it's a new feature that we're
requesting the Dark Factory to add into
the codebase.
So, we create a set of GitHub issues
like maybe there's you know 20 that are
created in the last hour or something
like that. And then on a scheduled
basis, I'm going to run the first Archon
workflow. I'm calling it the triage
workflow. Because the responsibility of
this Archon workflow
is to look at all of the GitHub issues.
And it's going to judge the issues
against the core governance layer that
I'm going to build into the the Dark
Factory repository. So, we're going to
have our our mission for the repo and
then the different rules. And these
files are going to also include the
scope that we're going to allow for the
codebase evolution. Like here are
features that we're definitely not going
to allow. Here are types of features
that we are going to allow. So,
basically the triage workflow
is going to evaluate all of the GitHub
issues that were created in the last
hour, you know, like everything that
hasn't been triaged yet and it's going
to figure out like you know, based on
our mission and rules, what issues
should we you know, put in a comment and
close and say like hey, this doesn't
apply for X Y or Z reason or here's an
issue that we're going to go into the
implement step. So, triage and then
we're going to have a separate Archon
workflow that goes through the full
implementation. So, for every single
issue that we decide we are going to
address, we're going to invoke Archon
workflows in parallel to do the full
implementation.
And so, again leaning on the beauty of
Archon here, we can handle any number of
issues in parallel because it each of
the issues are going to be handled in a
a work tree. So, we have full isolation,
full copy of the codebase for each one
of the issues to be worked on
independently without stepping on each
other's toes. So, we implement and then
for every single one of the issues that
we addressed, either a bug that we fixed
or a feature that we built, we're going
to have a separate Archon validate
workflow. So, this is where we do the PR
review before we do the merge into main.
And one of the things that Strong DM
implemented in their Dark Factory that's
very powerful is
what they call the holdout pattern.
So, the holdout pattern is the idea that
we don't want the bias from the
implementation to go into the testing.
And this is such a prevalent problem
with coding agents in general is they
will if you ask it to check its own
work, it's like asking a student to
check their own homework. They might you
know, give a little bit of feedback just
to seem like they're they are being
critical of themselves, but in the end
their bias is going to win out and
they're going to stuff the bigger
problems under the rug.
And so, what we do is a handoff. After
the implementation, we go through all of
our testing scenarios, but we don't tell
the validation agent what was just
implemented. So, we basically just do
regression testing over the entire
system. So, that way there's no chance
of bias cuz it doesn't even know like
what the issue was meant to address.
>> [clears throat]
>> And that sounds kind of risky and like
honestly myself, I'm not fully convinced
of this, but that that is Strong DM's
holdout trick and we're going to try
building that as well. That's why we
have a separate workflow for validation
and we don't just have it built into the
implementation.
Now, in Archon you can just like you
know, start fresh sessions between
nodes. So, I guess we could package this
up as one workflow and still have the
holdout pattern. Um that's one of the
things I'll just kind of have to explore
as I'm building with you guys. Like I'm
setting a lot of this up from scratch.
Like this is a live coding session. Like
I said, I'm not presenting something
that I've already built like I did with
Archon in the last live stream.
So, yeah, uh that's pretty much the
workflow here. So, I mean really it just
comes down to we have the governance
layer. These are pieces of context we're
always going to inject into every Archon
workflow. And then we have Archon
workflows to handle the full
orchestration here. Triage, implement,
validate, and fix.
And as far as the repository that this
is going to operate on,
it is going to be uh this one right
here. So, obviously I'm not going to use
Archon to work on Archon here. I don't
want to turn Archon into a Dark Factory
repository. It is too important that
that this doesn't just become an
experiment. So, there's a separate repo,
a separate project that I'm going to
build using the Archon workflows in the
Dark Factory.
And uh it's actually a pretty cool um
application. Like this is going to be a
huge value add for my YouTube channel
cuz essentially it's going to be a chat
platform, an agentic chat platform where
you can ask it any kinds of questions
around AI and then it's going to perform
rag. It's going to search through my
YouTube videos to give you an answer.
So, it's kind of like your own AI tutor
based on my content.
And then I was also thinking about doing
something for the Dynamis community. If
you are in the Dynamis community, you
can connect your account into this
platform. So, then not only would it
search over my YouTube content, but it
would also search over my workshops and
courses that I have in the community.
So, it'd become like the ultimate AI
tutor. So, it'd be like available to
everybody, but then it'd be even like a
nice value add to the Dynamis as well.
So, I'm actually really excited to build
this out. Um and so, if the Dark Factory
experiment doesn't work for whatever
reason, um and like I have faith in it,
but it is very risky. Like so, if it
doesn't really like build on anything
that like works super super well, then
I'm just going to you know, build it
myself with my usual AI coding process
cuz I want to have this by the end of
the month for everyone.
Uh but we'll see if the Dark Factory can
manage everything cuz I'm going to work
hard to build that initial AI layer. Um
let me actually refresh here cuz I I
already created the mission factory
rules in claw.md.
So, I'm going to work hard to build out
the
the governance [clears throat] layer,
build out the Archon workflows. I want
to make this as reliable as possible.
Now, the biggest risk that we have to
this Dark Factory
is that I can't actually use my
Anthropic subscription
because I would hit my rate limits way
too fast.
And if I want to make this public so
anybody can create GitHub issues
for the Dark Factory, I believe that
would be against the Anthropic terms of
service
if I let other people's GitHub issues
get automatically consumed into the
system, cuz then it's essentially other
people being able to use my Anthropic
subscription, because I'm not the one
starting the workflow. It's like
technically another user, I think. I
just want to be careful there. And I'd
hit my rate limits way too fast anyway.
So, I can't actually use my Anthropic
subscription for the Dark Factory.
And so, what that means is I have to pay
for an API.
I have to pay per token
for everything I have built in this that
I'm going to build in this Dark Factory.
And unfortunately, Opus would be way too
expensive.
So, I have to resort to other means. And
actually, what I came up with
is I'm going to use MiniMax M2.7
as the large language model driving the
entire Dark Factory.
Now, um
I've done a lot of research for
different models. I considered Qwen 3.5
Coder. I considered GLM 5.1. I thought
about maybe using like Sonnet, but
Sonnet would be too expensive. Um I was
maybe going to use Sonnet through
OpenRouter or just the Anthropic API
directly. Haiku would definitely be not
powerful enough. So, I I can't really
use an Anthropic model, right? Cuz like
Opus and Sonnet are too expensive. Haiku
is like significantly worse than MiniMax
M2.7, and they're actually a pretty
similar cost, I believe. Um yeah, cuz
like
if I go to OpenRouter here
and I search for Claude Haiku 3 or 4.5,
it is
um
$1 for every 1 million input tokens.
It's actually more expensive than um
MiniMax M2.7. That This It's less than a
dollar. Yeah, it's only 30 cents for
every 1 million input tokens. So, it's a
third of the price of Haiku and way
better. So, there's no reason if I'm not
going to use my Anthropic subscription,
there's no reason for me to actually use
an Anthropic model, because Opus and
Sonnet would be way too much.
And so, yeah, I I did a lot of research
and this is what I landed on. And I can
always switch the entire system, but
what I've done here
and this is part of the the setup that
I've already taken care of automat or
behind the scenes is I already have a
VPS spun up where I have Archon
installed. I have the rag YouTube chat
application cloned and and configured.
And then I have my Claude code
changed there
to use MiniMax M2.7 instead of
Anthropic. So, if I ask like here, give
me the SSH command. I'll actually show
you guys. I'll SSH into the machine live
with you and show you what it looks
like. So,
all right. I'll grab this command here.
All right.
Cuz take a look at this. If I go into
Claude,
I open [snorts] up Claude while I'm SSH
into this machine,
you can see that it's using MiniMax
M2.7. And if I say, you know, like what
model are you, everything looks like I'm
using Claude, but
or that I'm using Claude code normally,
but it is actually going and and using
my MiniMax API key and running on M2.7.
And by the way, if I wanted to use like
GLM 5.1 instead, it would be super easy.
Like I could swap over in like 30
seconds,
because all you have to do to swap the
provider for Claude code is you just
have to change a couple of environment
variables under the hood. Like And And
by the way, this session that I have
open with Claude code, this is on my
local computer where I'm doing some
setup locally. And what I had in the
session, I had it read my whole Dark
Factory plan. So, like everything you
see right here, it has loaded into the
context currently. So, I can just ask it
here, don't show any secrets, but tell
me exactly how I changed Claude code to
use MiniMax M2.7 instead of Anthropic
for the model.
Um so, I I might actually open source my
entire Dark Factory plan. Cuz as I've
been setting things up behind the
scenes, I've just been like documenting
everything in this like pretty massive
file here, including all of the Archon
workflows that I'm going to build with
you guys live right now. So, I have a
plan initially for every single one of
these. So, we'll build them today and
test them and maybe get to the point
where we have the whole Dark Factory
running. I'm not sure if we'll get that
far, cuz it's going to be quite a bit of
setup. Um but yeah, you can see that uh
for switching the provider for Claude
code, you just have to set these
environment variables. There There's
quite a bit here.
So, I think it actually would be pretty
useful to share this with you guys. Uh
cuz there were there was a
It was a little bit trickier than I
thought it would be to switch the
provider. Uh because then you The other
thing you have to do for Archon is you
have to map the environment variables
for the different model types. Cuz in
Archon, you know, for each of the
workflows, you can specify like for this
node, I want to use Sonnet. Or this
node, I want to use Haiku. And so, to
make the Archon workflows work out of
the box without having to change these
IDs, you just have to map it through
environment variables. So, like when I
specify Opus in Claude code or in an
Archon workflow,
that maps to MiniMax M2.7. Same thing
with Sonnet. And then if I want to use
Haiku, then it maps to MiniMax M2.7 high
speed, right? So, just a faster and
cheaper version of 2.7. So, I have the
same effect in an Archon workflow where
I can make some things a lot faster, and
then other things I have the most power
I possibly can.
Um like if I typically would use Opus or
maybe Sonnet.
So, yeah, if you are interested in using
Claude code with a different provider,
it's actually quite easy to set up. So,
you could have it use OpenRouter if you
want to use the Anthropic models there.
Um GLM has an Anthropic compatible
endpoint.
Um of course, MiniMax does as well. I
think Qwen does. Does Qwen have a Claude
code compatible endpoint? And if you
want to run local models with Claude
[snorts] code, you can use Ollama as
well. So, Ollama has a direct
integration with Claude code. So, it's
kind of cool, because we are planning on
adding Pi support this week for Archon.
So, you can run all of your workflows
through Pi agents.
And but even right now, you are able to
immediately switch Claude code to use
any models, so that you don't
necessarily have to lean on another
provider, but you're not stuck to using
your Anthropic subscription or the
Anthropic API key.
Okay.
Um
let's see.
Yeah, I don't think Qwen has Okay, but
like GLM and MiniMax
have the Anthropic compatible endpoints.
So, yeah, just ask Claude to do some
research for you. See like which ones
are compatible with Claude code, but
most models you're able to use directly,
like I set up with MiniMax here.
All right.
See what it says here. Yep, see yeah,
GLM has a first-party Anthropic
compatible endpoint. So, it's like
literally their API endpoint, and then
you just add Anthropic at the end. So,
that that's what you hit when you want
to make it compatible with Claude code.
So, pretty cool. It's It's pretty easy
to set it up.
All right.
Cool. So, uh yeah, I want to get into
building with you guys here.
Let me check the context. Maybe I'll
spend a little bit of time to answer you
guys' questions. So, I know I haven't
really looked at the chat yet.
Definitely want to do that. So, I'll
I'll spend a little bit of time doing
that, and then we can get right into
building out our factory. So, going to
the diagram here, I already have the
governance layer built out. And then as
I'm creating the workflows, I'll show
you guys what that looks like. So, right
now, I mostly just need to build out the
Archon workflows.
And it's important for all the Archon
workflows to like actually ingest these
documents here. Like it needs to know
like no matter what workflow I have
running, if I'm fixing something,
validating something, whatever, like it
has to always know the mission and
factory rules, cuz that's going to be
the primary guidance. And then I mean,
of course, the global like the Claude.md
as well.
So, yes, I am doing everything through
Claude code, but
I mean, you could easily make this Dark
Factory do like you use Code X or
OpenCoder Pi instead, but
yeah, it's just what I'm using. I like
using Claude code as a harness, even if
I'm not using Anthropic models.
All right. Cool. So, yeah, I'll leave
this up, and then I'll I'll go ahead and
hit some questions from the chat here.
And the future begins. That's right.
That's what we're building. We're
building the future here. I don't think
that that the Dark Factory is a pattern
that's reliable enough right right now,
but if we refine the workflows enough,
and if we have We'd probably need more
powerful models as well, honestly, to
like really make this production ready,
but maybe Mythos is going to be the
unlock. We'll see.
All right.
I'm level -11 or -1, not from a tech
background at all.
I mean, that's all good, cuz with how
powerful AI coding assistants are right
now,
you can get to level three
very very quickly.
And in fact, if you don't have a tech
experience, you probably won't ever be
level zero through level two, because
that requires you to write code yourself
sometimes. And so, these days when you
learn how to leverage AI coding
assistants and you're not coming from a
technical background, you just jump
right into level three.
My big recommendation with that though
is to ask your coding agent a lot of
questions as it's creating code for you,
so that you can start to gain an
understanding and like, you know, sort
of become at least semi-technical
yourself as you're using the tools.
Um will this video be saved for later?
Uh 100% Lennart's, yeah. So, every
single live stream on YouTube is
automatically turned into a recording
after. So, I don't even have to like
upload it myself. And so, I think it
takes a little bit of processing time,
but like what we have right here, it
says live right now, it'll be turned
into another video just like my live
stream this weekend. So, you just have
to go to the live tab. It's not in the
main video tab for my long-form content.
You just go over here
and then it'll be available for you.
All right.
I still feel like I need to test things
myself. I don't yet trust AI to test and
uh especially ship. I'm with you there.
Yeah, like I said, level three is where
it's at when you really care the most
about reliability. Unless you've built
some kind of level four harness that you
really really have faith in, I would
generally recommend sticking to level
three. And then level five is like no
one really knows how much this is really
going to work at this point. And that's
what I want to find out with you guys.
Like yeah, we have examples like strong
DM,
but they haven't they they've not really
shared that much, right? And like a lot
of it could just be like marketing hype.
So, that's what I want to figure out for
you guys for reals. Like if we actually
put a lot of effort into using Archon
and uh building a lot of reliability
through a governments layer, like how
reliable can we really make it? And I'm
excited to find out. We're going to do
it together.
Um you don't trust that if it's secure
or more than everything is working. I
mean,
okay, so sorry, this is a question
follow-up from the other one. But yeah,
I mean, I I would say personally that
like security is a big concern for AI
coding assistants. They do introduce
more security issues than uh seasoned
engineers. Um they can valid they can
fix them as well, but like first pass,
they introduce more. Um and then yeah,
just like generally that everything is
actually working. Cuz okay, here's the
other problem with AI coding assistants.
And then honestly, probably the main
reason that level five might fail, it's
not necessarily that the coding agent
produces code that fails, but it's more
that it's just not aligned with what you
want to create.
And that's part of why I'm going to be
focusing so much up up front on building
the governments layer because I need to
be very clear on the guardrails and the
guidelines for the coding agent so that
when it picks up an issue and implements
it,
uh first of all, I want to make sure the
issue is actually aligned with what I
want for the code base, for the
evolution of it. And then also like when
it does the implementation itself, it
doesn't misunderstand what the issue is
really getting at. Like if I open an
issue because I want to improve the rag
search, I don't want it to like change
the front end. I want it to just like
change the rag pipeline, for example.
All right.
See what else we got here in the chat.
Um I presume the dark factory can
introduce bugs later down the line if
proper unit testing, linting, and bug
regression system is is set up
correctly.
Um so, yeah, that's going to be one of
the risks of the dark factory as well as
there might be little problems that
creep in that our validation doesn't
catch and they might blow up in our face
later on. That's one of the reasons
human in the loop is so important for
reviewing things is to catch those
little issues that become a bigger
problem later.
Um so, the dark factory could kind of be
like boiling a frog in water, right?
Like the frog, if you put a frog in
scalding hot water, it's going to
immediately jump out of the pot.
And so, the analogy here is like if we
have a massive issue in the code base
right after implementation,
the validation is going to catch that
and it's going to address it. But if
it's something that slips under the
crack cuz it's not super apparent right
away, it's like the frog that you put in
warm water and then you boil it over
time. And so, it stays there until it's
dead.
>> [laughter]
>> Right? Like that could happen to a dark
factory. You have these these little
issues that creep in over time. It's not
big enough for the validate agent to
catch it, but then they combine together
to produce bigger problems or it's just
an issue that compounds on itself and
you're not there in the loop to find
those things and correct those things.
So, it's certainly possible. And uh as
much as we can, that's why it's it's
important for us to build a very
comprehensive validation process. Not
just with unit testing and linting, but
I'm going to be building in like full
regression testing. Like every single
time we handle an issue, I want the
validation to use a browser automation
tool to go through the rag chat
application like just like a user would.
And um like test this whole interface
and have different conversations and
click on the sources that it sites and
make sure that goes to the right part of
a YouTube video. Like I it's got to be
doing everything and constantly kind of
like maintaining this list of features
that it needs to test every time it's
doing proper regression testing.
So, we'll get there. That's going to be
probably one of the biggest challenges
to build for this whole thing.
All right.
Um also, it would be handy if you can
suggest open source or free alternatives
if available out there for the tools
we're using. As a learner, those crazy
bills make my heart sink. I'm with you.
I understand the pain for sure.
So, I I guess I'm curious like what
tools you're referring to exactly. If
you're talking about AI coding
assistants,
unfortunately, there's not really a a
free alternative to something like
Claude Code that's just as good as
Claude. Like I was talking about
earlier, I'm using Minimax M2.7 instead
of Opus cuz it's a lot cheaper. It's
still not going to be as powerful.
And if you really want like free AI
coding, then my recommendation is to run
a model in Claude Code through Ollama.
Like you can run Gemma 4, um Qwen 3 has
some smaller good models. You're not
going to get nearly as good of results
as Opus though. But like it is possible
to do AI coding free. You just have the
expectation that um you can't do the
same things that you can do with Opus or
some other more powerful model like
GPT-5.4 Codex in uh Codex, for example.
So.
All right.
Let's see.
Got only 1 year to experiment.
Oh, let's see. The comment above. I'm
thinking of creating some kind of
architecture for local businesses here
so I can and provide them. So, got to be
safe, easy to set up and manage for them
and myself and I don't get sued.
I have I'm curious what kind of
architecture you're talking about. Like
if it's an agentic system or if it's um
like if it's an AI agent or like for AI
coding.
Sounds cool though.
All right.
Gemini makes a good evaluator to run
against Claude.
Yeah, that is one of the things I want
to be experimenting in with Archon soon
is building workflows that combine
providers
so that we can do like exactly what
you're describing. Like Claude for
implementation and then Gemini, a lot of
people like using Codex for review as
well just to to have a
check on Claude. Um so, yeah, that's
going to come soon for Archon.
All right.
Cool cool.
Um
Was that Excalidraw in Obsidian?
Yes. My Excalidraw diagrams I always
have in Obsidian.
So, I'll show you that really quick. If
I go to the settings and go to my
community plugins here,
I use I just use the Excalidraw plugin
by uh Zsolt. I don't know if I'm saying
that [laughter] right. But yeah, I've
used this for a long time now.
Very very good. Cuz I just want to have
everything in my vault together.
Diagrams, research, everything. So, I
love using this plugin all the time.
All right.
Cool.
So, it little paywalled after all. Let's
see.
Right. For AI coding, if you want to get
the best results, it is paywalled right
now.
Um and I mean, unfortunately, it makes
sense. Like these frontier models like
Opus and GPT-5.4 Codex, they are
expensive, man. Like these companies are
burning through billions of dollars of
venture capital right now just to have
these models running for the world and
they're just starting to like make some
profits from getting it like the higher
levels of enterprise agreements.
Um cuz trust me, they they don't make
money off of your Anthropic subscription
if you are really maxing out your rate
limits for Claude Code.
Where they're really making the money is
using you as the lever to get the
enterprise agreements, the enterprise
interest.
So, they're they're profitable,
but it's it's very subsidized for our
Anthropic subscriptions. And that's part
of why they're
um jacking down the rate limits right
now. It's kind of unfortunate. It's uh
I'm not I'm not able to get nearly as
much out of Claude Code with my
Anthropic subscription compared to even
like a couple weeks ago.
Um the rate limits are are worse now,
unfortunately.
And they took away my 1 million token
Claude Code. That's another thing that
I'm kind of frustrated by. Um like if I
if I do slash model, apparently some
people still have this. So, I don't know
why it's just me, but I don't have the
option to use a 1 million Opus or or uh
Sonnet anymore.
So, I'd be I'd be curious if anyone else
has run into this as well.
But I am stuck to 200,000 tokens again
as of like just 3 days ago.
I don't know why. Or maybe it was like a
week ago.
But [sighs] yeah.
Anyway.
So, yeah. I'm going to have more time to
answer questions as we are waiting for
the workflows to be built here.
Uh one thing I want to put in the chat
quick is just a link to Archon. So, if
you're interested in checking out
Archon, like got some good content
on my channel.
Uh got the live stream from the weekend.
And then also I have the YouTube video
that I put out just 5 days ago on
Archon. So, check that out if you're
interested. Like I said, because I've
already done so much content, I'm not
going to be like hyper focused on
explaining Archon. I'm going to get
quick pretty quick here just into doing
[snorts] a live coding session creating
the Archon workflows with you guys.
Um and then also the repository that I'm
using the Dark Factory to build, this is
private for now.
Um well, no actually I made it public.
But, I'm not going to make it so that
you can give any issue to the Dark
Factory yet.
So, I'm going to start by having it only
accept issues from me.
And um then I'll make it so it's
available to everyone after I've like
tested things for about a week is my
plan. Something like that.
In fact, I I might actually want to make
this repo private right now.
As I build this as a safety measure.
We'll see. I I might have to switch it
private until I'm like confident that it
really is only handling my own issues.
>> [laughter]
>> So, we'll we'll have to
do that in a little bit. But, let's
start by building the Archon workflows
here.
Okay.
So, in my chat, how much do I have?
Okay, I have 40% of my context used. So,
I should be good to continue here.
So, again this conversation that I have,
it already has my full Dark Factory plan
loaded.
And so, I can literally just ask it like
what should I build next? Because I've
been keeping a log of everything that
I've created as I built it. So, like for
example, one thing that I already did is
I created the core governments uh doc
governance documents. So, I have like my
mission.md, factory rules. I can show
that to you guys like a little bit of
what went into that um as the workflow
is building. I just want to be efficient
with the time here.
All right.
So,
So, there's some things that I was doing
during an event in the Dynamis
community.
And then uh here's the remaining punch
lists from section 14. I told you it's
comprehensive. Section 14 of the plan.
Uh ordered by what makes sense to build
now and save for live.
Okay, so I guess there's a couple of
things that it recommended that I do
before the live stream here.
But also these are going to be super
quick
to set up anyway.
We need to create the GitHub labels, um
the issue and PR template, orchestration
shell script.
Yeah, I'm going to
Yeah, I'm going to have it rip through
all these things in parallel. So, okay.
The GitHub labels are actually kind of
interesting because everything in the
Dark Factory is going to be managed
through labels. So, when the triage
workflow runs, it's going to basically
check on these labels as a status. Like
this thing is currently being
implemented, right? Like don't don't
send off another Archon workflow to work
on this because it's already in
progress.
Or
worst case scenario, if it fails to
implement the pull request two times in
a row,
I'm going to have it labeled needs
human.
So, maybe I'm not making this like fully
fully Dark Factory, but I do want to at
least have like a small escape if I
really need to address something myself.
So, I have a little bit of a system
created for that.
And then uh yeah, like if I reject an
issue, like this doesn't fit with our
mission, or if I approve it and we're
not going into implementation yet, then
I'll add that label.
Um and then factory rate limit, I'm
going to have some protection to make
sure I don't blow through like hundreds
of dollars of Minimax credits in a day.
And so, if we need to wait for the next
day for the rate limits to subside that
I'm going to build into the system, then
we'll add this label as well. So,
yeah. It's a hard even in a live stream
to get like super deep into everything
that I planned here. But, I hope that
you can see from the the label system
that I have for these GitHub issues,
like there's a lot of thought that I put
into this system even handling like rate
limits and human escape if I really
really need it.
Um so, yeah. Really like the important
thing here is the GitHub issues are
driving the entire Dark Factory. Because
any kind of input into the system for a
bug that needs to be fixed or a feature
that needs to be created, the input
comes in from an issue. Whether that's
me creating it or the Dark Factory
itself creating the issue. Cuz we do
also have a sort of feedback loop here
where when the validation agent runs its
regression testing, if it encounters any
problems that are big enough to not just
be fixed right then and there, then
it'll create a GitHub issue and then go
through that loop and then address that.
And so, anything that it catches in
regression can just be more issues for
it to fix autonomously.
And uh so, yeah. I mean like hopefully
doesn't mean that we'll hit infinite
loops of creating issue and issue and
issue after issue, but might happen.
That's part of the experiment. We don't
we don't know what's going to happen or
what could go wrong. Um but that's why I
have protections in place to make sure
that it doesn't um that that just jack
me up in credits.
So, yeah. Like when I I have my balance
here, I I only put like 25 bucks to
start. And then I've used like, you
know, 87 cents in my testing so far.
It's pretty efficient overall.
But, I'm going to make sure that I um
yeah, never have like too much like I'm
I'm disabling auto billing.
So, that if I run out of credits, I just
have to manually
uh add credits and then I'll have the
system that like detects when issues
weren't handled cuz of rate limit and
it'll pick it back up basically.
Um okay. So, I'm going to say
uh so, I'll go into my speech-to-text
tool and I'll say, "I want you to create
the GitHub labels, issue and PR
templates, and uh the orchestration
shell script and cron entry on the VPS.
So, handle all these right now.
I'm actually in the middle of the live
stream now. And so, I will just explain
the workflows briefly as you do these
things."
All right, there we go.
It still thinks that I'm not in the live
stream yet. So, I'll give it an update
of of where I'm actually at.
>> [laughter]
>> Claude code doesn't really have a sense
of time.
Okay. So, while that runs,
who's paying for all this quota context?
I'm paying for it. It's it's coming out
of pocket, which is why I'm using
something very cheap like Minimax M2.7.
Yep.
Okay. So, let's see. Let's go back to
the Dark Factory plan. I want to show
you guys a little bit of what the Archon
workflows will probably look like. So,
what I have here,
these are very much rough drafts of the
Archon workflow. So, when I actually
build them in a little bit in our stream
here, they might end up looking quite
different.
But, when I was doing my initial
planning with Claude code creating this
whole Dark Factory plan, I also had it
load the primary Archon skill. So, it
knows how to build workflows. It knows
the different parameters, things like
that, how to use the Archon CLI. So, it
created the initial draft for them.
And so, there are four workflows that we
need in total. We have the triage
workflow. This figures out what GitHub
issues we actually want to address and
it handles the labeling and things like
that.
And then uh we have the implementation
workflow. I have to Gosh, I have to
scroll a while here. We have the uh
implementation Wait.
I already scrolled past it. Where'd it
go? Where's the header here?
There might be some malformatting.
Oh no, here it is.
Um
Wait a second.
Does this do the fix as well? Classify
apply decisions.
Oh. I think there might be a misordering
here. So, okay. Anyway, we also have the
validate PR workflow. So, this is what
we're going to run that we're going to
do the whole like hold out pattern for
validation. We're going to run this on
every pull request that's created from
the workflow that does the issue fix.
I thought that would be the second one.
That's why I'm confused right now.
Um I'm not sure of that. Maybe that
maybe it just misordered things. So, oh
oh yeah, it did misorder thing. Okay,
that's kind of weird. But, anyway, this
this should be the second workflow. I
don't know why Claude put it in the plan
in this order. But, our uh next workflow
is the one to actually fix.
Um No, it No, that's not it. This is
This is a workflow to fix issues that
happen during PR validation. So, if
there there are any problems that come
up when creating the pull or when
reviewing the pull request, then we run
this to address things and then push a
new change to update to the pull
request.
Um
And then we have the
comprehensive test. So, this is the
regression testing workflow.
And this one is going to take a lot of
tokens. So, I'm planning on running this
one only like once a day or once a week
because it's going to look through every
single possible user journey. Every
single way we can use the application
testing every single edge case, making
sure that it works automatically.
And then for any things that don't work,
it's going to create a GitHub issue.
Right. So, every time we review a pull
request, we are going to do a lot of
regression testing, but it's going to be
a more concise version of this workflow
cuz this is going to be like pretty
token heavy.
And then yeah, I guess the one thing
that I didn't do is I didn't create the
workflow for actually fixing the issues.
And I I sorry, I remember now why that's
the case. It's because there's a a
default GitHub fix issue workflow in
Arkon that I'm just going to use or
maybe make a little bit of an adaptation
for. But then for all the other
workflows, they have to be created from
scratch. So I apologize like Claude kind
of confused me here or I forgot the
planning that I did with it, but
yeah, we're going to creating the
workflows in a second here.
Okay.
Cool. So all three tasks are done. We
created the GitHub labels and the issue
templates
and then we created the orchestrator. So
we're we're basically going to create a
cron job that runs on our VPS every so
often. And whenever this job triggers,
it's going to uh basically prompt Claude
to use the Arkon CLI to invoke the
workflows. Like, "Okay, it's time to
triage our issues."
Or it's time to uh yeah, see this is the
default one. It's time to fix the GitHub
issue or it's time to validate the pull
request.
So we can go to the GitHub repository
here and actually check this out.
So if I refresh
uh well, here let's go to an issue. And
if I look at the labels for the issues,
you can see that we have all these
labels now. Factory accepted, approved,
in progress, needs fix, needs human. And
if we look in the dot GitHub folder, we
can see the pull request template. We
want to make sure that as the dark
factory is operating, it has a set
standard for what goes into every single
pull request description and every
single issue description.
Because being as consistent as possible
is one of the best ways to actually make
this reliable. So we have one template
for when we're filing a bug,
one for when we are uh you know,
requesting a feature. So if I were to
actually go and open an issue right now,
uh it asks me, "Is this a bug report, a
feature request, or should I just create
it from scratch?" And we're only going
to uh allow maintainers to to do this
type. So if I click on a bug report,
then you can see that it automatically
populates this form that's defined in
the template that Claude Code just built
for me. So now we have some structure.
We're enforcing certain things because
we want to make sure like if I'm going
to have this as a public experiment
where anybody can open a GitHub issue, I
I need some kind of expectations set for
what information you're providing. So we
have these required fields. So that way
there is actually enough context for the
dark factory to address the problem. And
if a template's not used, then I'm just
going to instruct the dark factory to
automatically comment and close the
issue.
So we're going to be pretty strict on
that.
All right.
Cool. So uh now we want to actually
build our workflows here.
The thing is I'm pretty low on context,
so I might start a new conversation to
do this.
So I'm going to just say
I'm going to build the Arkon workflows
in a separate context window. So just go
ahead and update the plan with what
we've just done here.
And then I'll go into a new Claude Code
session to build the Arkon workflows.
And while this runs, I can just open up
a new Claude Code and do that. So let me
close out of here, open up a new Claude,
and I'm going to copy the path to the
full plan.
I'll just put it at the start of the
prompt here.
And then the other thing is uh
hold on. Let me close out of this. The
other thing is I want it to
load the Arkon skill.
Because I want it to the Arkon skill
that I have uh it gives a full reference
to Claude Code uh how to build Arkon
workflows and best practices for doing
so.
And so I'm going to say
uh read the entire dark factory plan
that I gave you the path to.
We are now going to work on building the
Arkon workflows. And I want to start by
building the triage, the dark factory
triage workflow. So
I also want you to load the Arkon skill.
Um so you understand all the best
practices for building Arkon workflows.
Then I want you to give me a summary of
your plan for the triage workflow, all
the nodes, what models we're going to
use, what the prompts look like.
I and I want to just like have a
conversation here iterating on the ideas
for the workflow before we actually
build it.
All right.
So we're going to do a little bit of a
pivot loop.
If you have gone through the Agentic
Coding Course in Dynalist, you know what
I'm talking about. We're going to do
some exploration, some planning up
front, and then we're going to create
the workflow and test it.
I don't even really know how we're going
to test it exactly, but I'll I'll ask
for its uh recommendations once we have
it built. Cuz I might need to kind of
like
get the dark factory set up
incrementally.
Or maybe I need to like really run the
triage workflow on the issues I already
have
in the repository here and just like see
what kind of labels it adds and if
everything's working. And then I'd
probably have to ask it to also like
undo all of its work so that we can
still have like a blank slate of issues
that aren't aren't uh modeled with yet.
So we'll see what we have to do once it
once it builds it here.
All right.
Minimax is designed to minimax out those
credits.
I hope not. We'll see.
I'm down to switch to something else
like GLM if I need to.
All right.
Auto billing it messed up last month,
never doing it again. Okay, that's too
bad. I will keep that in mind, probably
not do that myself.
Um use the Minimax subscription, gives
good value for money. Okay, cool. Yeah.
I don't know I probably like if I really
want to scale this experiment, I don't
think I can use any kind of subscription
cuz I'll hit rate limits, but that's
good to know.
Cuz I might
I use Minimax on Ollama, testing it now.
Okay, that's very cool.
Yeah, I mean I'm using a the biggest
version of Minimax. I don't think that
would really be realistically
self-hosted. Like if I look up Minimax
on Ollama,
um yeah, they don't even offer you to
install this yourself. It has to run
through the cloud offering in Ollama.
But I I believe if you look up like um
there are self-hosted
options. You must be running something
self-hosted, right?
If I just look up Minimax,
um
Oh yeah, so maybe you are running the
biggest thing.
Cuz you I guess there's like local
options.
This has got to be huge, though.
Yeah, that's massive.
140 GB for the main thing. And then if I
if we were to look at a
Q4 quantization, oh wait, it's still 150
GB. That doesn't seem right.
But yeah, it's a 230 billion parameter
model. I'm not running that on my
computer, I'll tell you that.
All right.
Am I using local models for this? Nope,
I'm using Minimax. Well, I mean you can
host Minimax yourself, so it's an open
source model, but I'm using it through
the Minimax API.
Uh thank you very much for the donation,
Jared. Appreciate it a lot. Building a
dark factory because even the machines
refuse to work in light mode. Right.
That's a good one. That's a very good
one. And thank you for the donation, I
appreciate it a lot.
Um when using Arkon, is it needed to
have bypass permissions for Claude Code?
Uh yeah, cuz you're running the Claude
agent SDK under the hood.
You it's meant to be fire and forget,
right? Like you're not supposed to
babysit Arkon workflows. There's human
in the loop built in, but that's a
different thing. So I would use it.
Like you can limit the permissions of
Claude when Arkon runs through hooks.
And if you really want to like create a
settings.json to manage permissions
there, you can do that as well.
But uh yeah, usually I just do like YOLO
mode when I'm running Arkon workflows
and then I have like hooks that prevent
reading from dot envs and removing
directories and working outside of my
designated codebase, like the work tree
that Arkon creates.
All right.
Uh we have eight H100s, soon to get
H200s. That is very very cool. I'm
jealous. [laughter] I do not have an
H100. Uh certainly not eight of them.
That's awesome. Yeah, you're going to be
able to run Minimax for sure. I think
you could even run GLM.
How big is GLM?
I don't even know.
Um
Let's see.
GLM is 744
billion parameters.
If you have eight H100s, though, I you
would I think you'd be able to run.
Can you run GLM 5.1 on eight H100s? I
think you can.
Like that should be decent. Yeah, cuz
each one is 80 GB of VRAM. You're
sitting pretty pretty there.
Um I mean you might still need to
quantize it potentially.
12.4
tokens per second on HH eight H100s. So
it's not like super super fast,
but uh that's still very cool.
I mean that's that's impressive.
All right.
I have not even a 100th of an H100.
Same. Yep.
>> [laughter]
>> Those are expensive.
Yeah, so yeah, 640 GB
of VRAM. So yeah, you you I think you
would definitely
I mean, you'd want to probably quantize
to get good results, but still insane.
All right.
Cool. So anyway, let's go back to our
coding agent here
because it came back with a summary.
Okay.
I've read the dark factory plan section
4.2 on triage specifically and the
Archon workflow offering guide. Here's
my proposal design for the dark factory
triage before we build it. So our goal
here, this is important for us to all
understand,
is to batch classify untriaged GitHub
issues against the mission and factory.
So these core files that guide the scope
of work and things we're going to
actually care about and things we won't.
And then apply the labels and comments
deterministically.
So Claude makes the decision, or I
should say Minimax makes the decision,
but then we're going to have a
deterministic steps in the workflow to
automatically label and comment. Just to
make sure that everything works the same
way every time we run the triage.
So we're going to run the orchestrator
or runs when the orchestrator detects
open issues with no factory label. So
the orchestrator is the cron job. It
runs every so often and when it sees
that we have things that don't have a
factory label, that means it's a new
issue that our triage workflow hasn't
looked at yet.
So okay, we have five nodes.
We're going to uh fetch the issues in
parallel.
Fetch the rules. So we're going to read
in the mission and factory rules and
then take a look at the pull request
list cuz that'll also help us determine
what is already in flight.
Which this doesn't really make sense
because I think we should be able to
rely on the GitHub issues alone to
figure out what's already in flight. But
maybe this is just like a bit of an
extra safety check, so I guess it
doesn't really hurt to have it. But
anyway, so layer one
will do our classification. So it says
Sonnet here, but remember we have it
configured to route to Minimax when you
we specify Opus Sonnet or Haiku in the
Archon workflows. So it's going to
classify each one of the issues and then
we're going to have a bash step. So a
deterministic step that will take in the
JSON array of decisions that we have
from the structured output from Claude
code and we're going to loop over the
JSON and then use the GitHub CLI
deterministically to apply the labels
and then also the comments to the issues
as well.
Okay, so we we have uh bash steps. So
we're not using AI for layer zero as
well, right? Like we just run the GitHub
CLI
to search through all the issues.
We fetch the rules.
Get the open pull requests. It says
optional but useful.
I mean, it's fine, but I guess we can
keep it.
And then classify
the plan explicitly calls out scope
judgment against a written mission
requires nuance. Haiku often fumbles or
in our case the high-speed Minimax would
fumble. That makes sense. Cost is low
since we run on less than 10 issues per
batch in one call.
Fair enough.
Um okay, so
you can see that one of the things we
support in Archon workflows is defining
the exact output that we require from
the model. So this is like structured
output with more classic agents if you
guys have dealt with that before.
But the point of this here is that when
our coding agent goes through the
classification process, we need a
standard. I'm going to keep saying this
throughout our livestream here.
Everything is all about standards for
reliability. We need a standard for the
coding agent. It needs to communicate in
the same way every single time um how
we're going to label the issue.
So it's going to output an issue number,
the verdict, which is going to be either
accept, reject, or needs human.
It's right cuz need human it that's our
fail-safe if it has failed to address
the pull request multiple times.
And the priority
and then the classification, bug,
feature, enhancement, chore, or docs.
That's good enough for me.
And then we have the prompt skeleton as
well. So just telling it like when it
goes through the classification what
it's actually doing.
Um and then what the script is the bash
script is going to look like to actually
invoke the GitHub CLI to label and
comment on things.
And then it's got some open questions as
well.
Um okay.
So let's go ahead and answer these
questions. So a batch size of 10 or
five, let's do a batch of 10. And then
help me understand like if we have
actually opened up like 30 issues since
last time the orchestrator ran, is it
going to loop in Archon or what does
that look like?
And then should triage ever label
without closing on reject?
Plan says close rejected issues though
with explanation.
Um yes, we should definitely close
issues when we reject them. Yep.
Priority labels on need human. Currently
I apply them. Useful so you can see at a
glance which human review issues are
urgent.
Yeah, I think that they are definite
definitely worth applying priority.
Also help me understand how is this
triage workflow
going to know that we need a human,
right? Cuz like we talked about in the
plan how once the workflow or the pull
request has failed twice on an issue,
then we would say need human. So like
what does that look like exactly?
Okay. Man, these are some tough
questions. Should I include a type star
label or just lean on the existing
GitHub issue labels? The plan doesn't
mention type labels explicitly.
I'd add them. Cheap signal for later
filtering. Sure, yeah, we can add them
and make sure you update the dark
factory plan with that decision as well.
Duplicate detection scope. Right now the
classifier sees open PRs in current uh
issue batch. Should it also see recently
closed issues to catch repeat reports?
Costs more context but catches more
duplicates.
Um I would say we don't really need this
cuz if we rejected an issue before,
we'll probably just reject it again. So
we don't have to spend the context to
look through recently closed issues.
Um do mission.md and factory_rules.md
exist in the target repo yet? The answer
is yes. I did actually create them. They
are on the main branch.
Uh target repo path, which repo are we
building this workflow into? The dark
factory app repo, right? Not Dynamos
engine. That is correct and actually I
will give you the full path to the code
base here at the start of the prompt.
Okay.
All right, woah, that's a mouthful.
It asked a lot of questions, but okay,
this is good. This is good cuz
this is this is going to be a lot of
work. We have our work cut out for us
when we're building the system up front
because every single assumption the
coding agent makes is potentially going
to be drastic when we're at this level
of leverage creating our workflows and
governance documents up front. Like we
have to be very very intricate here. So
I know that it can it can seem like I'm
spending a lot of time on this, but man,
this is important.
Because if it doesn't understand how to
label things right or it's not using
GitHub issues in the way that I want it
to, the whole system is going to fall
apart. So I got to take time. I'm really
glad that it's asking me a lot of
clarifying questions here.
All right.
Cool.
I'm still playing with Gemma 4 on my AMD
395 for local.
Pretty cool. Yeah, Gemma 4 is good. Like
it is legitimately a an impressive
model.
Uh it is I yeah, the one of the most
popular ones right now on Ollama.
Um ooh, I actually haven't heard of this
one. Nemo strong cascade 2.
That's cool. Man, there's so many models
local models I want to try out right
now.
Um woah, the benchmarks actually look
pretty good.
Live code bench pro. It beats
wow, it beats quant 3.5 397 billion.
And it's almost as good as Kim K 2.5 a 1
trillion parameter model. Seriously?
That's kind of nuts.
Interesting.
Kind of want to try this one with the
the dark factory.
Okay, well anyway, I'm getting a little
distracted here.
All right. Yeah, that's exactly right.
Quality work up front makes for some
stellar loops and that is what I'm going
for.
All right, let's go back to Claude here.
Okay, so let me address your two help me
understand questions. No looping in the
Archon workflow itself. The triage
workflow is not a loop node. It's a
one-shot DAG that processes a single
batch and exit. Here's the actual flow.
Okay, so if if we do have 30 issues
opened in between orchestrator runs,
orchestrator cycle one is going to fire
triage workflows, process 10, and exit.
Orchestrator cycle two sees work in the
high priority lanes first. Only when
those are empty does it fall through to
the untriaged issues exist and run
triage again. Okay.
Uh so okay, this makes sense. So the 30
issue spike does drain across three
orchestrator cycles. So we do have to be
careful
because theoretically if there's like
more than 10 issues and like created
every single hour,
then it is going to just kind of pile up
and pile up. But I think this is
actually okay because I don't want
That would be unfortunate if there's
more than 10 created every single hour.
That's going to be so much work for it.
Um
Right.
Okay.
So, that makes sense. We can always
change the limit if we want.
How does triage know it to needs mark or
it needs to mark needs human?
You conflated two distinct escalations
in the plan. I want to make sure we're
on the same page cuz they're unrelated.
Flow A is triage time needs human. When
this workflow handles, the issue itself
is problematic at intake. The classifier
marks needs human when the issue is in
scope but ambiguous,
architecturally risky,
a product judgment call,
clearly the classifier's decision.
Okay.
I actually don't like that.
I don't If I really want this to be a
dark factory, I want it to either close
issues or handle them. I don't want it
to create this graveyard of issues that
need my review when I'm not planning on
actually reviewing them. So,
Okay. I want to be clear here. I don't
want to review issues unless there have
been multiple failed attempts to address
them. And so, for flow A, we should just
close these issues with a comment. Like,
if it's ambiguous or architecturally
risky or whatever, let's just make a
comment explaining that and then close
the issue.
Um and then I want you to check the code
base itself to see if it has dot arcan.
I believe it does.
And then Okay, one design requirement I
want your okay on. For the bash apply
decisions node, I'm going to have to
classify
I'm going to have classify write its
JSON output to the artifacts directory,
makes sense, as a part of the prompt
instructions, then I have apply
decisions read the file with jq instead
of relying on classify output
substitution. The reason being the
reason string will contain quotes,
apostrophes, new lines, and emojis and
arcons auto shell quoting um into a bash
script is a foot gun waiting to happen.
I mean, I guess. I don't Is that really
not a problem? I'll have to look into
that separately cuz that it might have
just identified like a something we
might want to fix in arcon. But anyway,
writing to a file bypasses the whole
quoting problem. It's one extra line in
the prompt and a jq recursive in bash.
Sound good. Uh sure, that sounds good
for me.
Okay, man, it's getting specific, but
that's good. Like, I appreciate how in
the weeds it is right now. That's That's
what we need.
All right. Cool. So, I think this is the
last thing I need and then I can
actually build the workflow.
Cool.
All right.
What else we got in the chat?
Thanks, man, for your shared work.
You're very welcome. It is my pleasure.
I love doing this stuff live with you
guys. It's so fun. Just sharing
everything.
And you know, I was a little bit um I'm
going to be honest, I was like a little
bit hesitant to do this live stream
because it's a bit slower than how I
usually roll in my videos and live
streams cuz I'm I'm building something
live and I definitely at the stage where
I'm taking something pretty slow.
Like, we're not we're not going to have,
you know, massive payoffs constantly
here. Um it's a slow and steady right,
it's a marathon, not a race. That's what
it is when we're building a system like
this up front.
Okay.
Um what now?
That was a lot of uh information.
Okay, confirm the execution plan.
Okay, makes sense. Scaffold arcon, write
the workflow,
validate the workflow, fix any
validation errors, and revalidate.
This is great.
Uh well, actually,
yeah, I'll just say this is good.
Go ahead. The other thing I was maybe
going to ask it is like, what's its plan
to actually invoke the workflow? Cuz
when it does the arcon validate, that's
just making sure the syntax is good. So,
it's sort of like linting of the
workflow. It's not going to run it yet
and triage issues, but once it does the
build, then I'll just have a
conversation with it and ask it what its
plan is to test it end to end.
All right. Cool.
I don't think we are too low on context.
Yeah, we should be good for it to rip
this whole thing. I wish I didn't only
have 200,000 tokens, but oh well.
All right.
Cool.
Can't wait till the Chinese firms use
missile mythos outputs to train their
models so open source local can really
go stratospheric.
Yeah, I mean, I'd be down for that.
So, yeah, if they would use mythos for
um
synthetic data generation like they used
opus, that that would be powerful.
They're probably going to. Screw the
lawsuits. They're probably just going to
do it.
>> [laughter]
>> Yep.
All right.
Can I do a session on hermies? I assume
you mean Hermes,
like the new like kind of like open claw
alternative.
Um I would consider it. However, I'm
more of a proponent of building your own
second brain versus using something like
Hermes or open claw.
And you know what, while we're waiting
for it to build the workflow here, I
think this is a good time to chat about
this quick. Let me actually um
Hold on. Let me open up a page in my
browser quick.
I think this is the right link. Yeah,
here we go.
So, one of the really, really exciting
things
that I did quite recently in the
dynamist community
is I did a 4-hour boot camp
teaching you how to build your own AI
second brain from a scratch.
And one of the things that I cover there
is how you can take inspiration from
tools like open claw or Hermes without
having to build run it yourself.
There are a lot of risks
involved in running your own or in
running a second brain that's not your
own application. There's a lot of
security problems with open claw and
Hermes, not just in like vulnerabilities
in the code base itself, but even just
running something that you don't
understand with permissions for your
agent that you don't also don't truly
understand.
So, I'm a big proponent of building your
own second brain from the ground up.
And that's exactly what I cover in this
course. And then I also edit it down
into a more polished 3-hour version that
still has like a lot of the good like
Q&A in it. So, that's in the community
as well as the third course for
dynamist.
So, if you're interested, like my second
brain literally saves me 20 hours a
week, like no exaggeration. It's crazy.
Like, I've been running my business for
about a year and a half now. Like, I
know how long it takes for me to do a
lot of these things that are like
partially or fully automated for me now.
And so, that's what I want for you as
well. That's what I cover in the course.
So, if that's if that sounds
interesting, let me actually put a link
to this in the chat for for YouTube
quick.
We've had a lot of people
joining the community recently. It's
very exciting for the second brain stuff
and also because of arcon. Uh a lot of
people are going to the course and
they're sharing their second brain, like
their own architecture and how they're
molding it for their use cases cuz I one
of the things I cover in the course is
like, here's how you build the
foundation of the second brain, but then
I also talk about how you can, you know,
guide it to help you build your own
integrations and skills and other use
cases that you have for it, even getting
into it being like very proactive for
you, anticipating your needs. So, yeah,
people are sharing their own use cases
and things. It's really cool to see.
Like, I'm learning a lot from you guys
even in the community itself. So,
outside of just how I'm evolving it on
my own. So, very, very cool. So, yeah,
wanted to call it out really quick.
Uh let's see where we are at with Claude
now.
Okay.
Everyone wants to sell a course.
Well, I mean,
I provide a lot of value. I stand by
what I what I provide there. So,
yeah, I don't I don't really appreciate
that the the cursing in the message
there.
Um but yeah, I mean, like I it
seriously, there's a lot of value that I
have and a lot of work I put into
creating that boot camp.
All right. Cool. So, anyway, here is
what we've got for the workflow. It
already built the whole thing. It's
actually faster than I thought,
honestly. But I guess we haven't really
done any validation yet.
Um let's see. So, we have our plan
updated with the little bit of changes
we made to the labeling system and the
changes we made to our plan for the
workflow.
Um and then
Okay, so we create the workflow itself.
>> [sighs]
>> Few implementation notes we're flagging.
But I don't want to spend like too much
time reading through this right now.
Okay, I think that's fine. What's not
done yet? Orchestrator agent.
Fix GitHub issue adaptation. Okay. So,
suggestion
for next step. Before building the next
workflow, I'd smoke test this one end to
end. Create the labels in the repo,
file one or two test issues,
and um okay.
That actually makes sense. But here
here's the thing.
Um I would love to smoke test, but I
already have some issues that I have in
the repository. So, maybe what we could
do is we could run the workflow to
triage those issues, but then just
delete the labels after so we can bring
us ourselves back to a blank slate. So,
I want to do the full test, but I I want
to like get it back to the original
state before I did my testing, if that
makes sense.
Uh but you can feel free to like iterate
on the workflow and everything before
you go back to the blank slate.
Okay.
So, yeah, I wanted to like actually run
it, but not like leave a mess of of
triaging and stuff. Cuz this repo that I
have right here, like I want to keep it
pure, right? For like when I actually
kick off the dark factory, like have all
the workflows built.
Okay. And then someone asked for me to
share the link for what I had open up in
Chrome. This is the link right here.
Um cool.
All right. Thanks, Cole. This is
awesome. I appreciate it a lot. Thank
you very much. Thanks, Cole. Will join
Dynamis.
Thank you. I appreciate it a lot. Yeah,
I'll be happy to have you in the
community. Watching at 5:20 a.m. from
New Zealand. Well, thank you for tuning
in so early. I appreciate that a lot.
Cool.
All right.
Let's see.
I I know it's a reference to shooting
yourself in the foot, but I've never
heard the term foot gun. Am I alone?
Actually, honestly, Chris, that's a good
point. So, that's in reference to what
Claude mentioned earlier.
Uh I guess I haven't heard foot gun,
either.
I don't know. Yeah, I've heard I've
heard shooting yourself in the foot a
million times. I use that expression
myself a lot, but yeah, I guess that's
just a shorter way to put it.
Cool.
All right.
Uh I definitely want to join Dynamis,
but just bought a house. Fair enough.
Well, congratulations, Stuart, on your
new home. While I'm trying to get
everything operating free and local for
a first run. Then once I have output, I
can pay for upgrades. Sounds good. Yeah,
fair enough. Yeah, congrats on the
house. That's exciting.
You're joining as well? Very cool. I
appreciate it. Welcome to the Dynamis
community.
Thanks, Cole. This is super cool. I
appreciate it a lot. Yeah, I I
appreciate you guys uh finding interest
in something where it's like a little
bit slower pace as I have to like really
spend my time ideating and and building
the system up front.
So, yeah, happy to to build this in in
public, so to speak.
All right. Cool. So,
let's see. The workflow is currently in
progress.
Looks good.
Um you know what I I kind of want to do,
cuz I'm running this workflow for the
first time, is I would love to uh view
the logs in the Archon UI.
So, let me actually ask it. I I don't
have it started I restarted my computer
recently, so I don't have it up and
running.
Start the back end and front end of
Archon.
This is how easy it is, by the way. You
don't You don't even have to run the
commands in the terminal or run the
containers or anything yourself. You
just let it go.
So, we'll take a look.
Okay.
I mean, bun run dev's not hard to
remember, but I just like doing that.
>> [laughter]
>> All right. So, let's head on over to
Archon.
Go to the dashboard.
Um it looks like the back end is still
starting.
Can you monitor the back end and let me
know if it's failing to start?
Not sure. I might be on a wrong branch
or something. Oh, no. Okay, I think
Wait, hold on.
Um
Why is my workflow not showing? I have
these uh
These workflows from way back in the
Saturday live stream that I forgot to
continue are still running. That's
funny. So, they're still paused, but
it's not showing up.
Where did it
Is it done running already?
Oh, okay. It did actually finish.
Huge win and a Windows bug. Let me break
down what happened. All three parallel
fetch nodes finished. Classifier ran in
30 seconds. Decision.json was written
successfully.
The fetch open PRs node paid for itself
immediately. It thought that the
classifiers would have accepted seven
issues that are already being worked.
What broke is the JQ uh failed on Git
Bash for Windows. Oh, that makes sense.
Yeah. Okay, so let's see.
Okay, so it's figuring out how to fix
here.
Caught another bug.
Okay. Now it's running the workflow
again.
It's cool that it's iterating. Like
little little blips that it's finding,
but like I mean, as long as it's able to
iterate, I'm happy with it. Um yeah,
okay, there we go. So, now we can see
the workflow. It's not running, but the
one that just failed, it uh shows up
here.
So, you can take a look at the logs uh
from the failure.
So, yeah, everything is working as
intended in the Archon web UI. We just
need to fix the syntax for the the
underlying workflow itself.
Cool. So, all right. Oh, now it's
running again. Okay, very good. View the
logs. Very cool.
Looking good. All right.
We'll see if it works this time.
All right.
Till foot gun means that. Yep, today I
learned as well.
Eric said the courses in Dynamis are
standing. I'm a career dev and seen a
lot of courses. Dynamis courses are
exceptional. Yeah, I appreciate it very
much. I I appreciate you guys like
sharing that, especially after someone
comes in and just like has to say
something mean for no reason.
Which I mean, I got thick skin. Like
it's fine. I I understand. And And by
the way, like to to that person who who
was a little mean, like I do get it.
Like I understand that like everyone is
just trying to sell a course.
Uh and and I can see how it just feels
like I'm just fitting in with that
crowd. Like I I get it. It's okay. I'm
not just like living in a bubble where I
I think that you're saying it totally
out of pocket. Like I understand. But
like at the same time, like I really do
believe that I'm not I'm it's not saying
I'm expecting you to do this, but like
if you were to actually go through the
second brain course, I I feel like you
would take back what you said. Like
honestly, I'm just going to say that.
Um but yeah, not not like I'm thinking
I'm going to change your mind or
anything.
Yeah.
All right.
Having never built anything before, but
amazed how easy this is to learn if you
think logically.
That's right. Yeah. And even just like
slowing down and using Claude code to
help you think logically. Like break it
down for me step by step. Or like help
me plan this and ask me questions. Like
those kinds of things are are uh how you
get the most out of Claude code.
Because it it can
I mean, like large language models make
mistakes. They're never going to be
perfect, and that's why you need to
align with them. But you can have them
walk you through the alignment process,
cuz they do a really good job at that.
Okay.
Uh cool. So, it looks like it ran end to
end, and it actually closed a lot of
issues here. So, three were accepted,
and then seven were rejected. Okay,
interesting.
Uh well, I'm curious to dive into that
now.
It says that it's still waiting here.
Cool. Smoke dev said as a part as part
of as a student of the course, I agree.
Dynamis is an absolute game changer for
me. Lots of value. I appreciate it a
lot. Thank you very much.
Uh
All right.
Cool. So,
uh looks like it is done.
Cool. And that was fast, by the way. It
didn't take that long.
Now, we we didn't run this workflow with
Minimax. Let me be clear, cuz we didn't
run this on the VPS yet. But we will get
there. We're just testing it right now
locally. In fact, I should probably test
my or check my Anthropic rate limit.
Uh oh, it's not even that bad. Okay,
we're good.
Here, I'll even share that on my screen
here.
Let me duplicate
and bring it over.
So, this is my limits right now.
Uh look at that. We've only We've
literally only used 10% so far. So, not
bad, especially without bad the rate
limits are. Um
Wait, what is this? Daily included
routine runs? This is new, like as of
just today.
Included routine runs per rolling 24
hours. I actually This This is weird.
I've never seen this in the usage page
before from the Claude app.
And yeah, my weekly limit, I'm at
already at 50%, and it resets on Friday.
And over the past couple days, I've been
doing so much testing with Minimax that
I haven't even been using my Anthropic
that much. Like it's crazy. I I got to
like 40% over the weekend.
Yeah.
Okay. So, anyway, I was going to look at
the classifications that it did here.
Oh, it already undid everything.
Shoot. So, I can't actually see
cuz it deleted the comments.
Okay, so this is one of the ones that
was accepted. So, we can see that the
labels are removed, cuz I asked it to
undo things after it's testing. But we
can see that from the history here that
like this one, it added the factory
accepted with a priority low.
If we look at um I don't know, one that
it rejected here.
Where is this one? This one, it added
factory rejected. Closes not planned. It
had it it an issue comment here at one
point. That's another thing that it
cleaned up. So, I honestly kind of wish
that it did the cleanup after I told it
to, but that's my fault, because I told
it to do the cleanup immediately after.
We can see here that um it has taken
care of all the cleanup.
All 11 issues are back open with zero
labels. But anyway, the workflow
actually worked extremely well.
Um okay.
What it did not touch. Yeah, that makes
sense. Ready for the next step. The
triage workflow is committable. Next
logical builds per the plan.
Uh get help label one-time setup for the
real run. Already done implicitly.
Dark Factory validate PR.
Well, it shouldn't the next step be to
create an adaptation of the Archon
GitHub issue fix workflow for the Dark
Factory.
Cuz I I think like I don't know why it
The plan wasn't really clear on like we
got to actually build something for
implementing the pull requests, not just
validating and fixing the issues that
come up. So, I'm going to try to point
it in the right direction here.
Um cuz I want I think that'd be the next
workflow to work on. So, we have the
triage, which is going to figure out
what issues do we actually want to
address, and then in parallel we'll
invoke the Archon workflows to
you know, take it from issue to pull
request.
Okay.
You're right, and I missed that. Of
course, Claude has to be sycophantic and
tell me that I'm right.
Um but I am.
The triage workflow will produce his
labels, but those labels are inert until
there's a working fix workflow that
knows how to validate.
Uh the plan calls this out implicitly as
a hard blocker. The moment a bug fix or
feature lands the default bun run
validate will still blow up on Python
syntax. Right. So, this this is a little
bit behind-the-scenes planning I was
doing. Basically, the fix GitHub issue
work
get fix GitHub issue workflow built into
Archon isn't quite specific enough for
my code base. So, I just need to take
this as an example. This is one of the
workflows that ships by default with
Archon, and I just need to tweak it to
work a little bit better with my Dark
Factory specifically.
So, it's going to do some research for
me. So, understand the structure of the
repo,
um understand the command or the
workflow that we're going to adapt, and
then see what we have for our global
rules already.
All right.
Let's see.
All right. Yeah, I appreciate it. Don't
care for such comments. You're really
delivering a lot of value for free as
well. I think we all value that a lot.
Yeah, I appreciate that. And um even
when I do have the community as a you
know, paid thing, I I do try to give an
insane amount uh for free.
Like what I'm doing right now. So, I
appreciate you recognizing that. And
that really is important to me. Like no
matter what, I always want to just be
constantly giving. That's also why
Archon is fully open source. This
repository has nothing hidden. I mean,
the Dynamis community had early access
to it and got to even help shape some of
the direction for it. And that's one of
the cool parts of having a community. Uh
but it's it's for everyone. That's
That's always been the goal.
All right.
Is there a link for the community? Uh
yeah, yeah. Sorry, I'll I'll send this
again here in the chat.
Um so, this this is a link to kind of
like the page like showcasing the AI
second brain, but you just scroll down
and there's a lot of buttons here to
join.
So, yeah. I appreciate that.
All right.
Let's go Sorry, I'll I'll watch the logs
here.
All right.
See, a strong DM depends on a digital
twin universe, which creates behavioral
clones of external services like Okta,
Jira, Slack to allow agents to run
thousands of realistic tests.
Yeah. Okay, if you really get into
StrongDM setup, it is quite impressive.
So, it certainly won't be uh building
everything StrongDM has, at least for
now. But also, my application is luckily
a lot simpler, where I won't necessarily
need to to have the same level of depth.
Right? Like simpler application means I
don't have to go as deep, but I still
get like the same reliability like they
built. Uh but yeah, if you want to like
really read into what StrongDM has
built, again, they haven't open sourced
their Dark Factory. But they've, you
know, open sourced the PRD like I showed
at the start of the stream. And then I
think they have like some blog posts as
well where they break down a lot of what
their architecture looks like.
It's pretty cool. It's It's really
inspirational.
All right.
Cool.
Um routine runs. Is that analogous to
OpenClaw crons?
I mean, probably analogous to some kind
of cron job. I don't know exactly. Like
this I've checked my Anthropic usage
every single day cuz I don't want to be
on top of especially the 5-hour rate
limit. This This I literally like wasn't
This wasn't there this morning.
Um so, yeah. I don't I don't know what
it is exactly. Maybe Maybe they have
something If I just like search Claude
code routine runs.
Okay.
Um oh yeah, here we go. 47 minutes ago,
we have a post
on the Claude code subreddit. New Now in
research preview, routines in Claude.
Configure a routine once, a prompt, a
repo, your connectors, and it can run on
a schedule.
Scheduled routines let you give Claude a
cadence and walk away.
Um okay, I was just about to say, they
already have the slash schedule in the
CLI. If you've been using slash schedule
in the CLI, those are routines now.
There's nothing to migrate. Okay, that
makes sense. So, they're they're taking
something that was has already been
there, but now they're just building it
into other platforms. Like I I assume
that like slash schedule used to be an
only CLI thing, and now it's like within
Claude desktop and co-work and the
Claude app.
I guess that's what it is. I I mean,
it's pretty cool. So, yeah, literally it
is cron jobs. Just being able to run
something that runs every hour
or day or whatever.
That's pretty cool.
All right. They are always shipping. It
is crazy.
But good for them.
Okay. Very cool. So, now
uh okay, how long have we been streaming
for?
Um we've been streaming for a little
over an hour and a half. Okay, so I am
able to stream for Wait, I got to check
my calendar. I'm able to stream for 2
and 1/2 hours. And I'm I'm loving what
we're building right now. So, I'm
thinking I'm going to go till Yeah, I'm
planning on streaming till 1:30
Central Time. So, like another hour
here.
We'll see how far I get
with all of our workflows.
Okay.
Shh. What are we doing here? Okay. Wow,
there's there's so much output. I'm
getting a little like
um burnt out on the like burnt out from
all of Claude's output here. It's a lot
to parse through cuz it's kind of it's
fairly complex what we're working on
right now, I will say.
Okay.
Reg YouTube chat's validation story is
prescribed, but not wired. Okay.
Uh global rules prescribe the exact
commands, but none of those dev steps
are actually installed yet.
No tests, no makefile, no CI. Right.
Yeah, I haven't built that yet.
The factory should add these when the
first PR touches them. I don't actually
agree with that. I want to build that
ahead of time.
I [laughter] love this. It's cute, but
it creates a chicken and egg problem.
Oh, that's funny. I Wow, Claude Claude
has some personality now, I will say.
Uh and yeah, I agree with Claude here
that that is a bad decision to put in
the global rules.
Um okay.
The bundled Archon fix GitHub issue
workflow is mostly language agnostic.
That makes sense. So, my surgical fix is
just one file.
My recommendation is option B, custom
command override.
Uh here's why. Okay. All right. Yeah,
sure.
Full workflow fork.
All right.
You know, so it's saying I don't need to
create a workflow from scratch, and I
can just use what I have as the bundled
workflow.
Um
Yeah. Okay.
Yes, you're right. We definitely want to
bootstrap the development dependencies
manually.
And then I actually do want to create a
custom workflow entirely.
So, yes, I know that there's not much we
have to change from the GitHub issue fix
workflow, but I want to be able to
evolve it separately from the default
Archon workflow anyway. So, we can
mostly copy it and then obviously just
changing the validate command, but yeah,
let's go ahead and and do it that way.
Um
Yeah.
And then sure, we can we can smoke test
issue number 26 after.
Okay.
There we go.
Um oh crap, we have to run the
compaction now. Oh, I forgot about that.
I probably should have just worked on
the workflow in a separate conversation.
Um cuz now that it does a memory
compaction, it has to reload its skills
and stuff. So,
All right. Now that you just did a
memory compaction, I need you to uh read
the Dark Factory plan again.
And then load the Archon skill. Just to
make sure you have full context before
you go into building the second workflow
and um doing the smoke test on issue
number 26.
Make sure you build this workflow from
scratch. And then uh also, I want to use
the commands folder for all Archon Dark
Factory workflows. So, make sure we
don't have inline prompts for the other
the triage workflow we just built as
well.
Um so, that's a little specific, but I
just realized that um I wanted to
organize my workflows a bit better than
I did up front if I go do the code base
now.
We have the Dark Factory triage.
Um this prompt is inline, and it's
massive.
So, I would rather extract this to a
command.
Right, we don't have any commands right
now, but in Archon, your workflows can
reference a command, which is just like
a separate markdown document. Just to
have a better way to organize things, so
we don't have have massive ugly prompts
in line in the workflow itself.
I might even want to do the same for
this. This apply decisions bash is like
really long.
Yeah,
there's there's a lot of optimizations
that I can make. Just for the sake of
the live stream, I am moving decently
quickly.
So certainly will be iterating on things
off camera
like before I make the YouTube video
tomorrow that kind of like you know sums
everything up for the dark factory that
I'm working on.
All right.
Cool.
I appreciate it. Haters going to hate.
Dynamis rocks and the value of your
contributions Cole are frankly
incalculable. I appreciate it a lot.
That means a lot.
Price of Dynamis is a lot more
reasonable than most of the courses
community subscriptions being offered. A
lot of them sound like snake oil.
Get rich quick for thousands of dollars.
Yeah, there there unfortunately is a lot
of that out there.
There there's one
sort of YouTuber in particular that I
don't want to call out exactly
or like name drop, but he he's a
respectable guy. He does a lot around
second brains specifically like even
before generative AI. A lot of you might
know who I'm talking about.
So I'm not saying the course is going to
be bad, but he like he's like running
these cohorts for building your own
second brain.
And he's charging $2,000 for it. It's
like
crazy. Like what? Like $2,000 just to
like learn how to build a second brain.
Like I taught that for
in a 4-hour workshop and you can just
join the community for it. Like
it's not $2,000.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
Anyway, there there are some pretty
expensive things out there for sure.
All right.
Will the dark factory repo be open
source after the live? So not fully
but it'll be within like the next couple
of weeks I will open source it. So I
need some more time to validate and
really polish things, but the plan is to
make it public by the end of the month.
Like everything public where you can
even open an issue and have it work on
it for you.
So
Who could I be talking about?
Yeah, yeah you got some of you guys
know. Some of you guys know. And and
again I respect him. Well, I guess I
would say I have more of a neutral
opinion. I haven't gotten like too deep
into his stuff. So I'm not like trying
to dunk on him or anything. I'm just
saying that like to me like $2,000 to
join a cohort is a little ridiculous,
but
to each their own. I mean some some
people
definitely
value having that kind of like cohort
style.
It's yeah, to each their own.
All right.
Okay, let's see here. What else we got?
The old you're absolutely correct. Yeah,
that's right.
All right.
Bit out of context, but
could we build a skill to make Claude
code and and anti-gravity interoperable?
You definitely could. Like if you wanted
anti-gravity to invoke Claude like in
headless mode, you could if you wanted
to.
I think I don't know [snorts] if
anti-gravity has like a CLI, but Gemini
has a CLI obviously. So
you could have them invoke each other.
So you could like have a workflow where
it's like Claude implements the code and
then it calls the Gemini CLI to do the
validation. Like you could do that kind
of thing 100%. Like that's something
that I actually want to build like
directly in the into Archon workflows.
Like being able to have different
providers at different nodes for
planning and implementation and
reviewing.
All right.
Okay, this is really interesting.
MiniMax with open code performs much
faster and better than in Claude code.
Probably the context blow of all the
prompting that goes under the hood in
Claude code.
So that Okay, that's good to know cuz
yeah, maybe I would want to change this
harness to use like Pi or open code
instead.
Okay.
I I will have to look into that. Like I
said, there's so many ways that I can
probably improve this harness
with the prompting and how I organize
the workflows and my mission document
and my factory rules and even just the
tool that I'm using under the hood. Like
maybe I do want to use Pi or open code
instead.
All right.
Let's see.
One way to find out if the course or
subscription you paid for justify the
cost is if you ship a product that
others paid for to recoup that cost. I
mean yeah, exactly.
That right cuz then then it's like
there's no argument there. Like if you
made more money thanks to what you
learned there
and you built something from it then
yeah, pays dividends. Exactly right.
All right.
Why does it feel like we've been here
for 1 plus hours and not achieved much?
I mean that's something that I've been
trying to be very transparent about here
is that like we're spending a lot of
time planning and defining the
architecture and the system for the dark
factory up front. And it it has to take
time. It it has to. I can't rush it. And
and to be honest like I would probably
be going even slower
if I wasn't in a live stream here
because in the end like if I want this
thing to rip through issues really
quickly, if I want the dark factory to
be self-sustaining and really efficient
and reliable, I have to be slow up
front. That's what I'm and that's kind
of the the teaching lesson here honestly
as well.
So
Yeah.
Even miracles need time.
It's a good way to put it. I would I
feel like that'd be very egotistical to
call this a miracle. It's certainly not.
It's just an experiment that we'll see
what happens, but yeah, it's a good way
to put it.
All right.
That's very cool John. I joined Dynamis
two months ago today, never wrote a
single line of code, have a functioning
second brain.
And yeah, that's that's awesome John. I
appreciate it. Once you get to that
point where your second brain is up and
running and saving hours and hours every
week there is no better feeling. So
good.
All right.
One of the basic rules of marketing is
people are willing to pay for high
ticket. I mean that's fair. Yeah, like
this individual that I mentioned
I mean maybe I could just say his name
cuz I'm really not like hating on him or
anything, but I just for the sake of
being careful.
I'm sure there are people that get a lot
of value out of it and and yeah, he he
like kind of is known as like the
premium person.
He's like he's been building second
brains for a decade.
I mean I would like to think that like
he's struggling to catch up with all the
AI stuff cuz he he's more traditional in
his approach. He's probably doing fine,
but anyway like yeah, I'm sure there's
When you when you have something high
ticket, it signals value and so you do
attract that kind of person that is
willing to shell out
and they just want to make sure like I
mean I don't always agree with this, but
like sometimes people just think like
hey, most money means it's the best
value.
Definitely isn't always true, but it
does kind of scream like this is going
to be the safest bet if you have the
money for it. I don't know. I don't
know. Kind of rambling on that, but
Yeah.
Uh
Dynamis is awesome. I'm part of the
community since it came live. That's so
cool. I appreciate you being a part of
the community for so long.
And by the way, the 1-year anniversary
of Dynamis is this month, April 26th.
So there going to be some some exciting
things that I've got going on for that.
Some live streams I'll be doing on
YouTube around the time
and also some exciting events in Dynamis
and some things that I am releasing as a
part of the anniversary celebration.
Also just speaking of things that are
going on around that time,
I want to call this out really quick as
well. I'm doing a This is kind of
unrelated, but around the same time.
I'm doing an AI transformation workshop
with
a gentleman named Lior Weinstein on
April 28th. So that I believe that's a
Tuesday at 9:00 a.m. [snorts] Central
time.
So this is going to be really cool
because
Lior he's like an expert at coming into
a company and helping it become AI
native.
And so like designing like an AI native
org chart and like how to enable each
team and team member with AI
technologies for coding and other things
like even just like you know the sales
and marketing and finance team and all
of that.
So he's going to like talk about that
for an hour and then for an hour I'm
going to talk about how to transform
your organization with agentic coding
and like how to transform developer
teams. So we're going to kind of take
team it together to give you like this
full view of like how you transform
companies and even yourself as an
individual.
So that's going to be really cool. So
that's happening at the end of this
month here.
And yeah, like you can see I'm on my you
know scheduled live stream page of my
channel. Like this is just going to be a
free workshop just [clears throat]
happening on live stream on my channel.
All right.
Cool. Yeah, big shout out to Cole. Even
the content you're delivering for free
every week is insane. Thanks a lot.
Yeah, you're very welcome. Always my
pleasure. Man, like I've been doing
YouTube for
it's almost 2 years now. I started like
very beginning of July 2024.
And it's just a blast. Every single
video is just so fun to make and
keeps me ahead of the curve on
everything too. Just being a constantly
in the trenches building and researching
and doing what it takes to make the
content for you guys.
All right.
What is going on now?
>> [laughter]
>> Uh, sometimes it's stressful to come
back and just see like it's in the
middle of writing the package.json. You
don't even know why.
Oh, I guess it Oh, yeah, it's setting up
the developer dependencies that we
talked about. Okay, we're good. We're
good.
So, okay, what has it done now? I think
it made the full workflow.
Yeah, okay. Dark Factory fix GitHub
issue. Okay, good. So, we got our second
workflow now.
All right.
Dynamis Oh, no, not that one. I need to
go to
the rag YouTube chat. I want to open up
the second workflow.
Okay, take then this is good. So, now we
have all our different commands. So,
instead of the workflow just being like
a bunch of massive inline prompts, uh we
got it organized a lot better.
Okay, so this is our fix GitHub issue.
By the way, I'm thinking about renaming
the whole
uh rag YouTube chat repo to Dyna chat.
That's why it references this name a
couple times.
Uh but anyway, so
this workflow here, we're going to start
by extracting the issue number. So, this
is very much based based on the default
fix GitHub issue workflow in Arkon. Then
we classify the issue, bug, feature,
enhancement, refactor, chore, or
documentation, just like we planned in
the in the Dark Factory plan. Then we
research the issue.
Uh and then we either do a plan, we
create a plan if it is a feature to
build, or we investigate the problem if
it is a bug to fix, right? Cuz issues
are going to be one of the two.
Right? So, like when we classify, it's
either going to be a bug, and then I
know we have all these different labels,
but basically all these are just feature
additions, right? Like if it's a chore
or a refactor or an enhancement, like
all those are just like more specific
versions of a feature. So, may maybe the
whole like issue labeling isn't
optimized here, but I think it's fine.
It's actually pretty standard to have
those kinds of labels.
And then we go into implementation, then
validation, create the pull request, and
we review. And so, I am going to have a
separate workflow to do complete pull
request validation, but I still want to
have the workflow it's like when the PR
is created, at least have it do a little
bit of review, right? So, like initial
round of review here, and then it'll
have a more comprehensive validate PR
workflow that I'll create next. That's
the plan.
Just to give it a chance to do a little
bit of self-fixing before we say like,
"All right, here's our pull request for
for you, uh you know, next stage of Dark
Factory to review."
All right.
So, let's go back to our coding agent
here.
Where am I going? Okay, there we go.
Okay, status so far. So, we refactored,
built the new workflow, seven new
commands.
Looking good. Got our dependency set up.
Uh okay, before I kick off the smoke
test, two things to confirm. Dev
dependencies are not installed locally.
Um
okay, that's fine.
Yes, I want you to install the dev
dependencies. And actually, I would much
prefer to use UV for the Python package
management, so go ahead and change that
in the repository. Get everything
installed and test everything.
And
um
and then yes, go ahead and invoke after
that invoke the Arkon workflow to run
the Dark Factory fix GitHub issue on
pull request or no, on issue number 26.
Okay, yep, that's good. All right, cool.
And then we're not going to have time
for it in the live stream here, but um
you know what I
I'm almost tempted to do another live
stream tomorrow instead of a YouTube
video. Maybe. I probably should make a
YouTube video cuz it it'll be a week.
Uh but it'd be cool to like just keep
building this live more. I know that
it's a lot of time, but it it's it's fun
to do this, and we're getting kind of
close, right? Like we have a lot of it
built. We just need to finish the last
couple of workflows, and then we need to
bring everything onto the VPS so that we
have the whole Dark Factory running
autonomously, and it's not relying on my
computer being on. So, we're we're
getting there. We're getting there.
We we won't really be unfortunately be
able to see everything running on our
VPS today,
but um
it won't take long once we have the
workflows built and validated to copy
everything over cuz we already have the
I think this is my directory, Dark
Factory. Yeah, yeah. So, we already have
the app here. So, we we already have
everything like cloned and set up and
verified. So, we just have to bring over
the workflows and then set up the cron
job that's going to run every hour to do
the triaging and then the implementation
and everything. Like it it should
work pretty quick once we have the
workflows built. And that's why I wanted
to use Arkon for this because then I'm
not even creating the harness myself
from scratch. I'm just building Arkon
workflows, and that is the harness. It's
a clear example of the value of Arkon as
a harness builder, which is part of the
reason I wanted to do this Dark Factory,
by the way, is it's just such a cool use
case to show the power of Arkon. Like
these workflows are defining processes
that would actually take a good amount
of time to architect from scratch. If we
wanted to like, for example, even just
having this process of triaging issues
and then sending off
MiniMax to handle each one of these in
parallel, like that would take a lot of
engineering if we didn't have Arkon as a
starting point to bring in the context
and handle work trees for isolation so
we can build each one of them in
parallel. And then having the
deterministic steps to uh you know,
label the issues and close issues, like
that that's a lot of work, but now we're
able to just rip through this like
pretty quick. Like I know that it that
the stream is like 2 hours now, but
still like when you really think about
how much we've already engineered here,
like it's a lot that we've built
already, and we've taken our time with
it.
All right.
Um
>> [laughter]
>> Can we use Arkon and the Dark Factory as
paperclip?
So, yes. You could.
Cuz each Arkon workflow could be like
the
the you know, individual AI employee,
kind of like how you manage that with um
paperclip. You could.
That'd be cool. It's kind of what I'm
doing, I guess. Like each Arkon workflow
you could sort of think of as a
different employee. I mean, we literally
have the pattern here where we're doing
the about the holdout where it's like
this has to run completely separately
from the implementation. So, it is sort
of like two different AI employees that
the the Dark Factory is delegating work
to.
Smooth as fast. Mistakes are 10x as
expensive as planning time. That's
right. Pays dividends take your time up
front.
All right.
Let's see. Learned a bunch about rag
from you early on. Yeah, I still cover
rag somewhat, not as much anymore, but
it is still important. A lot of that old
content is still very relevant, too.
But yeah, I used to I definitely used to
be like the rag guy back in the day, but
especially when I first started my
channel.
Yeah.
The appearance of value is very
important. 100% yeah. I had a relative
doing art and selling at craft shows.
She switched to art shows and made a
living off of it and has pieces in
museums. That is so cool. Yeah. Right,
so it kind of goes back to our
conversation earlier, like when you have
something priced at high ticket, like if
you have the good appearance of value,
you can price it high, like 100%
Yeah.
All right.
Providing unique individual value via
video platforms, cohort platforms, etc.
is the norm of the future, not the
exception.
Yeah, I mean, people will crave
individual attention and personalization
more and more over time as AI takes it
away in some parts of life, so
I can see what you're saying. Yep.
Um
Maybe Cole has an AI-proof job. How many
people would watch this stream if his
second brain was doing it alone?
>> [laughter]
>> Oh, that'll be the day. I don't I don't
know if I would ever want to have my
second brain run a live stream. Also, I
would it wouldn't look good right now.
But I mean, there are people that have
AI avatars do videos, not necessarily
live streams, but even that, like it
just looks bad. I I don't I don't think
that it's really feasible.
>> [snorts]
>> Um unless like
for some reason people are okay with it
being an AI avatar cuz you're just like
delivering the news or something. I know
that that's usually what most AI avatar
channels, they are just like AI
news-focused, right?
All right.
If you're paying 2K to learn how to use
Zettelkasten, then you may need more
than a second brain.
Uh
That's funny. Yeah, I don't I don't
know, like you can get pretty deep with
Zettelkasten. I know myself personally,
I've only scratched the surface. I have
actually taken inspiration from
Zettelkasten a little bit for how I've
organized my Obsidian vault.
But yeah, it's definitely something I I
personally like I agree, I feel like you
can just figure it out on your own if
you have a good head on your shoulders,
but again, to each their own. I'm I'm
trying to like avoid getting like super
opinionated on things that like I know
that like there is value
but
yeah, it just depends how much you want
to just like get the best practices
right away versus like figure out
yourself over time. I guess is what it
comes down to.
All right.
What else we got here?
Yeah, okay. So this is exactly why I
built my own get up issue fixed workflow
for just now.
The default Archon commands are very no
JS centric and that I think that is
something we want to improve to make it
a bit more language agnostic or a lot
more language agnostic.
I can see arguing with itself to build
my go laying app.
Yeah, so I would recommend right now. I
mean just in general it's good to build
your own hardness. Build your own
workflows cuz then you can customize it
more.
I would recommend building your own and
using the ones that we have as defaults
as a starting point. So you can point
your coding agent to the default Archon
workflows and say look at these for a
best practices and even like leveraging
the structure for fixing issues or
creating PRDs or validating pull
requests.
And like use that as a starting point
and then make it specific to my
validation flow or my tech stack or my
architecture.
Yeah.
Cool.
The AI co-host.
Okay, that could actually be
interesting.
If I had my second brain not like run
the stream but just like be there as a
peanut gallery or something more
practical like kind of giving feedback
in real time or even like answering some
questions in the chat.
I could Okay, that could actually be
kind of cool. I should think about that.
How I could have my second brain co-host
a live stream with me.
That would be cool.
Hmm. Okay, I'll think about that. I will
definitely think about that.
Okay. All right, where are we at now?
Um oh, it's still going. Jeepers.
All right.
Well, I guess Oh, yeah, cuz we had the
memory compaction. So that slowed things
down a lot.
Okay.
>> [snorts]
>> I'm I just wanted to
Okay, I'll let it keep running here.
All right.
Then you don't need me anymore. No, no,
no. I still I still want real people to
help co-host live streams with me. So
Thomas, he's the guy that I have the
comment highlighted for and then also
Rasmus. They've done a lot of amazing
work helping me on Archon.
And I have said that like for some
Archon live streams, I'd love to get
them in to co-host.
And I still stand by that. There's no
way if I get my second brain to help
co-host with me, it would be a different
kind of thing and a different sort of of
value proposition for the live stream
compared to having a real person like
you or Rasmus co-host with me. Like I
would want to do both 100%.
Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> All right.
All right.
Let's see.
We got some interesting feedback here.
All right, let's take a look. Once you
take this to production, it will just
hallucinate success at every step. LLMs
give the most plausible answer. They
rationalize anything they can't reason.
This whole video is from 2025.
All right, hot take hot take but no, I
appreciate the pushback.
Um because what you're saying has some
validity and that's why I'm calling it
an experiment. And that's also why I'm
spending so much time up front planning
the system and the architecture.
Because yes, one of the biggest problems
with large language models right now is
that they are sycophantic. They always
agree with everything that we say and
they have an insane amount of bias
towards their own opinions. They're
going to rationalize everything and
there is a risk if we don't build the
system right that they're going to say
that this thing is ready to merge and
then it's going to merge it and then
it's going to move on to the next issue
and we go through this loop where every
single time it's producing AI slop. That
is a risk.
But that's what I'm trying to engineer
for here.
I'm putting so much time up front
because I'm doing things like defining
the holdout pattern for validation. So
that I'm taking away for some of this
I'm taking away from and preventing some
of the sycophantic behavior. Because
when we go into our regression testing,
we don't even know what was just built.
And so it's just going to be a
neutral judge. At least that's the goal
of what we're doing here. There's still
a risk to it 100% and that's why I'm
very clear at the start of the stream
here that when we go to this level of
autonomy for our coding agents. Like
going back to the five levels here, the
dark factory here is not what I
recommend if you want the most reliable
software possible. We might get there at
some point and maybe this experiment is
going to be a wild success and it's
going to be like whoa, dang. Actually
this can get us a really good, you know,
MVP for any application.
Maybe. But yeah, I'm I'm not I'm not
like numb to the fact that sycophantic
or sycophancy is a big problem and we
have to be really careful about that.
So I I feel pretty confident in the
approach that I have here. I think we
are going to avoid a lot of that bias
and a lot of shipping things that it
says are good when they actually aren't.
It's not going to be perfect but that's
also why I have other strategies. Like I
have the like really deep regression
testing that I'm going to run every day
or every week and then create more
issues to address that. I still am going
to have some human in the loop for the
very very end. Um where I actually want
to like push things to a platform that
people are using. So I'll have a little
bit like I've thought about a lot of it.
So again, I appreciate the pushback.
But trust me, I'm I'm considering it all
100%.
Okay, let's go back.
Still working. Wow, okay.
All right.
Anime girl co-host. You'll never see me
do that.
>> [laughter]
>> It's funny though.
All right.
You have to check the parameters to
themselves introduce the specific
parameters to check. Yeah,
extra math and type of engineering
checks to achieve it.
A little lost on what you're getting at
there. Maybe you could elaborate.
Uh need to drop off. Good session Cole.
I appreciate it.
Yeah.
All right.
Cole the rag guy, spicy mangoes. Yeah,
spicy mangoes hasn't come up for a while
but I'll have to bring it in to another
video soon.
Um
An LLM can't even join
a a chat room
without everyone knowing instantly it's
an AI. I mean yes, that's true.
Yep. That's that's why I wouldn't ever
have a stream of having a second brain
run anything anytime soon.
Yep.
All right.
Let's see.
Hard to explain. Yeah, all good. Yeah,
take your time.
All right.
Yeah, okay. I agree with this 100%. If
an LLM hosted a show, it would be boring
and bland and obviously an LLM. I mean
yes, I agree.
All right.
Um cool. So okay, anyway, our coding
agent is done here. So I want to come
back and and give it some more
attention.
So all right, we're done with all of our
dev dependencies. The smoke test
problem. Dark factory validate currently
runs whole code base checks. If I kick
off the workflow on number 26, the agent
will
fix the one line score bug then validate
will hit 130 pre-existing errors didn't
create.
Um okay.
So wow. Okay, so I guess what what
happened here is we're creating the
development environment for the first
time. So there are a ton of issues that
aren't actually related to the fix that
we'd be running the workflow on. So I I
need to actually address these things.
Um
Yeah.
Let's do number one. Let's address all
the problems and then run the workflow.
Yeah, I just I mean this will take a
while.
Um but I I do just want to do that cuz
cuz what I might be able to do is
actually create the next workflow in
another Claude code session here.
I think that makes the most sense.
Let's go ahead and do that.
Okay.
So let me go back to my vault
and copy the path again
to our plan file.
So I'll say read this plan file
and also load the Archon skills. You can
help me build more Archon workflows.
I have just finished creating my dark
factory adaptation of the fixed get up
issue workflow. Now I want to work on
the validate PR workflow and it's very
important that this follows the holdout
pattern very closely.
I just had someone in the live stream
say that they don't believe in this
approach and I think the holdout pattern
is one of the most important things to
address their concern. So let's let's
focus on that.
I'm being a little silly but but yeah, I
think it's it is very important that we
make sure that we are taking lessons
from the strong DM dark factory cuz it
is it is very impressive.
All right.
Let's see. What else we got in the chat
here while I wait for this to run. We'll
kind of monitor these two sessions in
parallel here.
Um is there a way to use Quen 3.6 plus
with Archon even if it's through open
router?
So uh one thing I learned the hard way
recently with open router is you're not
actually able to use Claude code with
open router for any models outside of
the Anthropic ones cuz it doesn't have
an an Anthropic um compatible endpoint
like MiniMax and GLM.
So if you wanted to use Quen 3.6 plus I
would wait until we have support for uh
Pi. Pi is going to be the third provider
that we add this week or next into
Archon.
Because then you'll be able to use other
models really easily. You're not going
to be like the obviously like right now
we have Claude and Codex and you're a
little bit more vendor locked. You can
do what I did in the VPS to point it to
other providers but only if they are
Anthropic compatible like MiniMax and
GLM.
So there might be a way but I actually
tried first before I went to MiniMax
directly. I tried going through open
router and it didn't work.
It only worked when I chose an Anthropic
model.
Um okay.
It's confused here because it's trying
to read my workflows in the remote
machine but I haven't actually pushed it
to remote yet.
I might need to. Hold on.
Oh no, hold on. It figured it out. We're
good. We're good. All right.
I need a new open source 120B.
I mean yeah, it's been a while since we
had one around that size for sure.
Yeah.
All right.
Um since I love C
what do you think about Blitzys and
their C compilers?
Um I don't Do I love C? I haven't
programmed in C for a very long time.
Actually it's been about 5 years since I
programmed in C.
Uh you mean like C the programming
language?
I assume cuz you're talking about C
compiler. I I haven't used C in a long
time. I also haven't heard about Blitzy.
I'd be interested though. Um
funny story or not funny but interesting
fact for you guys.
Um when I was in college I was a
teacher's assistant for a C and machine
learning course.
So I I got to uh not sorry, not machine
learning. Goodness. A C and assembly
course, machine architecture course. So
I got to help students debug assembly
code for hours and hours a day.
>> [laughter]
>> At one point that was fun.
Yeah.
All right.
So all right, what did it What do we got
now? Have enough context. Let me lay out
what I'm building. So holdout pattern
design for the dark factory validate PR.
This is the critical workflow for
defending the AI writes code on
supervised concern. Here's how I'll
enforce strict holdout across five
layers. Okay, so this is the main
concern that we're addressing here with
AI sycophancy in our dark factory.
Not saying this is going to be perfect
but this is my first attempt for the
public experiment to avoid the coding
agent just always saying its work is
good and merging it.
So we have a separate Archon workflow,
separate artifact directory, separate
work tree. There is no way that it can
peer into the work of the other agent
and potentially take its bias.
So we exclude comments and review. No
code no coder chatter.
Uh we have our our governance files.
So we're going to read those as our rule
book.
Every AI node is going to start with
fresh context. So every step of the way
during the validation we're not even
going to build up bias in the validation
itself through the different nodes.
The behavior behavioral validation
command leads with a holdout rule
section enumerating what it must not
consider. It can't find and search for
implementation plans, commit messages,
coder rationale, prior review comments.
It answers exactly one question. Does
the diff solve the issue body?
Very good.
And then even another holdout pattern I
I was kind of referencing earlier is
like when we do the full regression
testing every day or every week it also
is going to have no knowledge of recent
feature implementations or issues that
we're in the middle of addressing,
right? Like it just is going to answer
the the straight question of like does
this application work with all the user
journeys we have laid out in the mission
markdown?
Good.
All right. So now it's writing
everything and we'll let it go. Both
both of these are still running
actually.
So
I'm going to open up the repo again.
Cuz I can I I just want to show off the
uh mission and factory rules just like
really quick.
So here's our mission document. So it
it's uh decently concise, not too long
but it covers um like the core of the
application. What is DynaChat?
Um who is it for?
Uh patent still pending by the way. I
might not keep the name either. We'll
see. We'll see. Uh who is it for? The
core capabilities of the applications.
This is specifically calling out what is
in scope. Like if I were to create an
issue to add Google OAuth to the
platform the triage is going to be like
oh yeah, good. Let's mark this as
accepted because it's literally in the
scope for the mission.md.
And then we also cover what is out of
scope. What must the factory never
build? Like we don't want it to add
other YouTube channels. Like if someone
created a GitHub issue we'd want that to
be rejected because
at least for now. I mean I could extend
this application later but at least for
now the scope of this app is for my
YouTube content to be a resource for you
guys.
We don't want to you know allow someone
to open an issue to swap the LLM. That
would be bad for my credits.
Uh we don't want to like add in payments
or subscriptions. Like this is meant to
stay free. We don't want to
overcomplicate with a mobile app or a
desktop desktop app. Like no like
electron or Tauri app.
Um so yeah, it's like things that we
don't want to build.
Uh hard invariants. Like things that we
have to we absolutely have to keep the
same so we can't allow for issues that
would try to tweak the rate limiting or
the authentication requirements, things
like that.
Uh ways we're allowing it to evolve and
then quality standards.
Right? Like that that's our mission.md.
And then I can evolve this over time.
This is sort of like my console. So like
going back to the analogy here of like
you have a car that doesn't even have a
steering wheel. Well you're still going
to have some kind of console to provide
higher level directions. And so if I
want to tweak the dark factory
I still have the levers to pull because
I can still change the factory rules or
the mission.md or I can update the
Archon workflows. So if I really want to
and there's like a drastic issue that I
just really need to fix I can make a
commit myself just straight to the main
branch. So I mean there's flexibility
with this here.
Uh but yeah, that's And then the factory
rules. This file governs how the dark
factory operates on this repo. So like
here here's how we handle triaging,
right? Like this is more context that we
it's quite important to feed into the
triage workflow.
Here's how we implement things. Here are
our requirements for pull requests. For
example, I don't want to allow more than
500 lines cuz I want every single issue
to be a small focused scope of work.
That's one of the most important things
for getting reliability out of our
coding agents here.
Quality gates for auto merge. Uh
uh talking about the regression testing.
I want to use the agent browser
specifically.
This is the Vercel agent browser CLI.
It's an open source browser automation
tool that I use a lot to test my front
ends especially when I'm working on
Archon itself. I'm using the agent
browser skill. So I want this to be
built into my larger regression testing
workflow. It's going to
Uh protected files that it's not allowed
to change, right? I don't want it to
change its own governance documents cuz
this is my console, my lever to pull,
not its own.
Um how like rules around like when we
should auto reject certain things.
How we should escalate, cost and
throughput. I mean I don't need to get
like super deep into everything here but
uh yeah, you can see like the factory
rules gets more specific. Like this is
quite a few lines of code here.
How many is it in total?
Uh sorry, not code, lines of markdown. I
got Even this isn't like super long but
it's 320 lines cuz there's quite a bit
of specificity I want to supply there to
really have my guardrails defined.
All right.
Have I you tried using prompts
that presume failure and laziness? It
can rationalize that too.
Um I mean I've I've played around with
that kind of thing in the past.
Um
it can rationalize that too. Are you
saying that like that actually doesn't
work or are you saying that uh that
helps it rationalize or like helps it
address problems?
Let's see.
You may want to leverage all your work
with rag and build graph rag as the
second brain. Obsidian as a second brain
doesn't come close to graph rag but
Obsidian is less set up.
Yeah, I mean I've found Obsidian enough
for me and like it's nice cuz it is less
set up like you said but I mean, maybe
at some point I will build a whole Greg
graph rank system for my brain and share
it.
Could be cool.
I still kind of wrestle with that might
be over engineering.
Depending on, you know, how much context
you're storing in your brain.
But I have that in the back of my mind
for sure.
Oh, it does work. Okay, cool. Yeah,
yeah. I mean, that's a good idea then.
So, like my validation process, I could
have a workflow in the dark factory that
says like, "Okay, I need you to assume
or like not even not even tell it to
assume." I just say like, "This agent
was lazy. Go and figure out why it's
lazy, what could be better about the
implementation, and then like open up
another issue or resolve it directly."
All right, that I like the idea of
building that in for sure.
All right.
Could I use Karpathy's auto research to
improve the dark factory in the future?
Uh tell plot twist it does not stop
running and starts replication.
Right. Some Yeah, maybe it will, who
knows. Um so, yeah, I could use
Karpathy's auto research.
Basically, if I were to apply Karpathy's
auto research, it would be a separate
process that has control over actually
editing these three files.
Right? Cuz like the idea behind auto
research is you have a a file that kind
of dictates a larger system, like a
model or a repo. And then that file you
have a coding agent iterate on
autonomously based on lessons that are
learned from a feedback loop. So, I
could build Karpathy auto research to
like evolve these over time.
So, like right now within the factory
rules I have that that hard rule where
it's not allowed to
It's not allowed to change the govern
governance, the constitution. But this
is only for the agents that are dealing
with the issues in pull requests. So, I
could have a separate process that like
its actual sole job is to evolve the
governance over time.
It's an interesting idea. I don't know
if I want to take the autonomy that far
right now cuz I really want this to be
the lever that like only I am pulling on
currently, but that could be a a natural
evolution at some point. It'd be
interesting for sure.
Cool. Yeah, I appreciate all the ideas
you guys are sharing here seriously.
Like there there's so much to chew on.
That's why I love this experiment
because
like the world becomes your oyster for
the ways that you can evolve this and
the things you can build with it as
well. You can really apply this to any
workflow and it's just cool being able
to like use Archon to guide the entire
thing as well.
Um like every single line of code that's
written here is written from an Archon
workflow.
So, yeah. All right. Uh let's go back
and see where we're at now.
Um okay.
So, we built our third workflow here.
And uh what's this one? This one is
Okay, so this one is in the middle of
actually testing the
uh the second workflow that we built.
Cool.
So, probably have to wait a while for
that to happen. I think I'm going to go
ahead and call the stream here though
because we'll have to wait a while until
we have like the next big thing
happening. So, I'll keep working on this
after the stream and then I'll be making
a YouTube video on this as well for
tomorrow, which I'm excited about.
So, yeah. All right.
Uh let's go back to full frame here.
I appreciate all of you guys being here
today. This is a very different live
stream to to build and like actually
take my time with something. I've not
really done that on a live stream
before, so yeah, I appreciate all you
guys' ideas and and questions as well.
And um yeah, for anyone who didn't get a
chance to get their question answered,
like always feel free to comment on a
video, join the Dynamis community as
well cuz I'm active there every single
day.
Uh maybe I'll just show that uh one more
time
really quick here.
I'll put a link once more in the chat
here cuz yeah, if you want to build your
own second brain, go through the agenda
coding course, just ask any question
that uh you have. Like the Dynamis
community is the place for it. So, I'd
love to see you there. Um otherwise,
I'll I'll go back to my full frame here.
But yeah, more live streams coming as
well.
Uh because I I actually enjoy doing live
streams more than making YouTube videos.
I like both, of course. I love both. But
I love doing live stream. I love being
live with you guys.
So, yeah.
All right. So, yeah, with that,
appreciate all you guys being here. Uh
stay tuned for the YouTube video
tomorrow on the dark factory with Archon
and more live streams coming up soon.
Hope that you guys have a great rest of
your day and I'll see you all around.
Have a good one, guys.